在下界放置水的唯一方法是将水倒入炼药锅
The only way to place any sort of water in the nether is by putting water in a cauldron.
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
♥无偿翻译，用爱发电♥
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
！！真的有人看不到这行字！！
不清楚为何或如何实现这一点
Not sure why or how this is possible,
不过倒也合理
but fair enough.
若背包已满时投掷带有忠诚附魔的三叉戟
If you throw a trident with the loyalty enchantment while having a full inventory,
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
三叉戟会一直跟随玩家
then the trident will just follow the player around.
该视频已删减部分与“500个我的世界老玩家应该知道的事”
视频重复的片段。原视频完整时长为2小时30分
铁傀儡在水中不会溺水
Iron golems are not able to drown in water.
你还好吗伙计？
You okay there, mate?
我觉得他没事
I think he's fine.
将盔甲架放在栅栏上会导致其悬空漂浮
Putting an armor stand on top of a fence will cause the armor stand to float,
看起来相当诡异
which looks rather strange.
当末影螨最初在1.8版本加入我的世界时
When the endermite was first added into Minecraft in version 1.8,
它们直接沿用了蠹虫模组的模型
they used the exact same model as the silverfish mod,
只不过颜色不同而已
but with just a different colour.
玩家能在一格空间爬行的特性其实是个意外诞生的功能
The feature of players being able to crawl in one block gaps was actually created by accident.
然而 Mojang 实在太喜欢这个意外特性  最终决定将爬行功能保留在游戏中
However, Mojang liked this accidental feature so much
that they decided to keep crawling in the game.
早在我的世界Beta 1.8版本时期
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft in beta 1.8,
当时创造模式存在一个漏洞
a bug existed in the game in creative mode.
不知为何 玩家能用剑从超远距离攻击生物
So for some reason, players were able to hit mobs
with their sword from a very long distance away,
这看起来确实有点诡异
which was just a little bit weird.
你看看这个
I mean, just look at this.
这怎么可能实现？
How is this even possible?
草径是隐藏物品的绝佳选择
Grass paths are a great way to hide your items in Minecraft,
因为它不是完整方块 物品能透过草径被漏斗吸收
as you can transport items into hoppers
through the grass path due to them not being a full block.
棕色蘑菇非常独特
Brown mushrooms are unique,
它能发出1级亮度
as they will emit a light level of 1,
而红色蘑菇则完全不发光
whereas red mushrooms do not emit anything.
如果沙砾落在灵魂沙上
If gravel falls onto soul sand,
沙砾就会自动碎裂
then the gravel will break.
戴上苦力怕头颅能将其探测范围缩小50%
You can reduce a creeper's detection range by 50% if you are wearing a creeper head.
大概苦力怕会把你当成同类吧
I guess the creeper thinks you're one of them.
哦等等 当我没说 它还是想干掉我
Oh wait, never mind, he still wants to kill me.
船的合成配方是唯一无需任何物品  就能在配方书中解锁的配方
The crafting recipes for boats are the only recipes
that can be unlocked in the recipe book without having any items.
你只需要跳进水里就行了
All you do is just simply jump into water.
当我的世界迎来十周年之际
When Minecraft became 10 years old,
游戏里所有蛋糕上都出现了数字10
all cakes in the game had a number 10 on it,
看起来就像这样
which looked like this.
即使玩家处于隐身效果下  蝙蝠依然会飞走
Bats will still fly away from the player if they are under the invisibility effect.
我是说 现实中的蝙蝠听力超群
I mean, bats in real life have amazing hearing,
所以这很合理
so it makes sense.
使用时运III附魔时  沙砾必定会掉落燧石
Gravel will drop flint 100% of the time if you use the fortune 3 enchantment.
在我的世界中 玩家穿过一个蜘蛛网需要漫长的13秒
In Minecraft, it takes 13 long painful seconds for the player to fall through one cobweb,
这简直...
which is just...
有人能把这个打破吗？
could someone break this please?
我的世界中的物品更惨  穿过一个蜘蛛网需要整整24秒
Items in Minecraft are even more painful as
they take a long 24 seconds to fall through a single cobweb.
快给我钻石 现在就要
Any time now, I want my diamonds.
当我的世界里的小熊猫打喷嚏时
When baby pandas sneeze in Minecraft,
它们有0.1%的几率掉落粘液球
they have a 0.1% chance to drop a slime ball.
在我的世界中  你可以用骨粉来复制两格高的花朵
In Minecraft, you are able to duplicate two block tall flowers by using bonemeal.
只需对高茎花右键使用骨粉  砰的一下就复制好了
Just simply right click on the tall flower with bonemeal and bam,
你就能无限复制这种花了
you can get an infinite amount of that flower.
当末地传送门首次加入我的世界时
When end portals were first added into Minecraft,
它们原本长这样
they originally looked like this,
呈现蓝色并带有透明斑块
appearing blue with transparent patches.
说实话 这造型还挺酷的
I'm not gonna lie, they look kinda cool.
如果玩家生成一个我的世界存档
If the player generates a Minecraft world,
那么再次生成完全相同世界种子的概率是280万亿分之一
then there is a 1 in 280 trillion chance of you generating
that exact same world seed for a second time.
没错 概率极低 但确实存在可能
So yeah, very rare, but still possible.
要塞里的单个图书馆恰好有233个书架
There are exactly 233 bookshelves in a single library within a stronghold.
这意味着玩家拆光整个图书馆的书架后 最多能获得699本书
This means the player can yield up to 699 books
when they destroy every bookshelf within one library.
在1.9战斗更新的15w31a快照中
In the 15w31a snapshot for the 1.9 combat update,
玩家可以通过用粘土搭建苦力怕脸来重生末影龙
the player could respawn the ender dragon by building a creeper face made out of clay.
这个功能当然只是个占位设计
Now this feature was of course a placeholder,
但依然非常酷炫
but it's still really cool.
当铁傀儡生命值偏低时
If an iron golem is low on health,
对其右键使用铁锭即可为其治疗
then you can heal them by right clicking on them with an iron ingot.
感觉好些了吗
You feeling better now,
伙计？
mate?
我可太喜欢铁傀儡了
I love iron golems, man.
击败末影龙后生成的末地折跃门
The end gateway portal that generates after defeating the ender dragon
are usually entered when you throw an ender pearl at it.
通常需要朝其投掷末影珍珠才能进入
不过更简便的通行方式是  直接在基岩上放置活板门  然后强行挤进去
However, an easier way to travel through the portal is
to simply place a trapdoor on the bedrock and force in the crawling position.
完成这个操作后
Once you've done that,
爬进去就能瞬间传送
just crawl through and bam,
你就能找到一座末地城
you can find an end city.
如果你仔细观察铁轨转角处的纹理
If you look closely at the corner rail texture,
你会发现它酷似一把铁镐
you'll notice that it closely resembles an iron pickaxe,
这设计其实相当酷炫
which is quite cool actually.
我的世界中有多种不同类型的台阶
There are many different types of slabs in Minecraft,
但史上首个被创造出来的台阶  其实是泥土台阶
but the first slab ever created was the dirt slab,
它的外观长这样
which looks like this.
但我们终究没能等来泥土台阶
We never even got the dirt slab,
愿它安息吧
so rest in peace.
基岩的纹理其实就是石头纹理
The bedrock texture in Minecraft is just the stone texture,
只不过对比度调得极高
but with a really high contrast.
在我的世界早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
想要获得宠物猫  得先在丛林生物群系驯服豹猫
cats were instead obtained as a pet by taming an ocelot in a jungle biome.
但在1.14版本更新后
But then in version 1.14,
流浪猫成了独立生物  直接在村庄里刷新
stray cats became their own separate mob and spawned in villages.
在1.9战斗更新的快照阶段
In the snapshot phase for the 1.9 combat update,
当时船存在一个漏洞
a glitch existed when it came to boats.
所以当玩家把船放在粘液块上时
So if the player placed a boat on a slime block,
等待几秒钟后
waited a few seconds,
然后进入船中
then got into the boat,
你就会被弹射到高空
you would be launched up into the air.
而且等待上船的时间越长
Also, the longer you waited to get into the boat,
弹射高度就会越高
the higher you would be launched,
这简直太酷了
which was so cool.
这是我的世界地牢结构的  第一张历史性截图
This is the first ever screenshot for a Minecraft stronghold structure.
如你所见 这座地牢外观相当独特  而且罕见地生成在了地表
As you can see, the stronghold looks rather different and has also generated on the surface,
这与我们现在的地牢结构截然不同
which is quite a change to the strongholds we have today.
如果你仔细观察我的世界中的快捷栏
If you look closely at your hotbar in Minecraft,
会发现每个物品槽都使用了沙子纹理
you'll notice that each slot is using the sand texture.
说实话 我第一次注意到这个细节时惊呆了
I won't lie, this blew me away when I first noticed this.
猪灵能够开关门
Piglins are able to open and close doors,
老实说这其实挺吓人的
which is actually quite terrifying to be honest.
我们都知道动物被火烧死时
So we all know that when an animal dies to fire,
会掉落熟的食物
it drops its cooked variant of the food.
但当动物被营火烧死时
However, when an animal dies to a campfire,
却会掉落生肉
it drops the raw variant of the food,
说实话这确实有点奇怪
which is rather strange to be honest.
爬行功能使用的动画与游泳动画完全相同 两者看起来都很棒
The crawling feature in Minecraft uses the exact
same animation as the swimming animation and both look awesome.
在创造模式物品栏中 耐久III附魔书同时出现在工具标签页和武器标签页
The Unbreaking 3 book appears in both the tools tab
and the weapons tab in the creative inventory.
音乐唱片11的播放时长正好是1分11秒
The music disc 11 will play for exactly 1 minute and 11 seconds.
在1.14.4版本中 船存在一个漏洞：每次在船上跳跃时
In version 1.14.4, there was a glitch with boats where each jump you made on top of a boat,
上岸行走时会累积坠落伤害
fall damage was added for when you walked on land.
比如 我在船上跳4次然后上岸
So for example, if I jump 4 times on top of the boat and then walk on land,
就会受到2颗心的伤害
I will take 2 hearts of damage.
没错 利用这个漏洞 你完全可以通过在船上跳跃来杀死自己或朋友
So yeah, with this glitch you could essentially kill you or your friend by jumping on boats.
被驯服的狼默认项圈颜色是红色
The default collar colour for a tamed wolf is red.
不过在1.8版本中
However, in version 1.8,
被驯服的狼默认项圈颜色不知为何被改成了橙色
the default collar colour for a tamed wolf was changed to orange for some reason.
输入数字0作为种子时 系统会随机生成一个种子数值
Trying to generate a seed using the number 0 will just give you a random seed number.
这意味着获得数字0作为种子是不可能的
This means that getting the number 0 seed is impossible,
对吧？
right?
其实 并非如此
Well actually, no.
所以如果你用以下种子生成世界
So if you generate a world using the following seed,
然后在游戏内输入指令/seed
then type slash seed within the world,
你会发现种子数值实际上就是0
you'll notice that the seed number is in fact 0,
这说明确实有可能获得0号种子
which shows that it is possible to get the 0 seed.
当杀手兔最初加入我的世界时
When the killer bunny was first added into Minecraft,
它在自然生成时有1/2500的几率出现
it had a 1 in 2,500 chance to naturally spawn in your world.
但如今它只是个未被启用的生物  只能通过指令生成
However, nowadays it's just an unused mob and you can only spawn it in using commands,
说实话这有点可惜
which is a bit of a shame to be honest.
如果你在熔炉里烧制湿海绵时
If you smelt a wet sponge in a furnace,
往熔炉里放个空桶
then put a bucket in the furnace,
当海绵烧制完成时  桶会自动装满水
then the bucket will be filled with water when the finished sponge is smelting.
在我的世界早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
也就是Alpha和Beta时期
in the alpha and beta days of the game,
骷髅持弓的姿势是这样的
skeletons used to hold their bows like this,
看起来非常非常诡异
which looked really, really weird.
羊仍然能够透过半砖吃草
Sheep are still able to eat grass through slabs,
你到底是怎么做到的 老兄？
how on earth are you doing this mate?
我的世界中最稀有的生物群系是经过变种的丛林边缘地带
The rarest biome in Minecraft is the modified jungle edge,
这是丛林生物群系中极其罕见的变种
which is an extremely rare variation of the jungle biome.
这个生物群系稀有到仅占主世界百万分之一  也就是0.0001%的面积
This biome is so rare that it only covers a millionth or 0.0001% of the Minecraft overworld.
正如你们所知  当箱子最初加入我的世界时
As some of you know, when chests were first added into Minecraft,
它们原本是一个完整的方块  看起来是这样的
they were a full block looking like this.
但你们知道吗  老版本的双联箱子中间  其实有一条黑色分割线
But did you guys also know that the old double chest had a black outline going down the middle,
就像这样？
which looked like this?
如今我的世界里的双联箱子  已经没有了这条分割线
Double chests in Minecraft today do not have this outline.
鞘翅的设计灵感其实源自  超级马里奥64中马里奥穿戴的翅膀帽道具
The elytra wings are actually a reference to the wing cap item Mario wears in Super Mario 64.
顺便说一句 这游戏真棒
Great game by the way.
当末地石最初加入我的世界时
When end stone was first added into Minecraft,
它最初会掉落圆石作为占位物品
it used to drop cobblestone as a placeholder.
我的世界中的猫比豹猫体型略小
Cats in Minecraft are slightly smaller than ocelots.
在我的世界基岩版中
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
基岩版还有个独家特性  下雪时树叶会变成霜白色
there is an exclusive feature where leaves will turn to a white frosty colour when it is snowing.
太酷了
Okay, that is awesome.
为什么Java版就没有这个特性呢
Why can't Java Edition have this feature,
这是蜘蛛在游戏中的首张截图
This is the first ever screenshot of spiders.
它们最初是棕色的 还长着黑色眼睛
They were originally brown and had black eyes,
而如今游戏里的蜘蛛是黑色身躯配红色眼睛
whereas in Minecraft today they're black and have red eyes.
猪是我的世界现存历史最悠久的被动型生物
The pig is the oldest existing passive mob in Minecraft.
如果生物手持不死图腾
If a mob is holding a totem of undying,
那么它的效果将与玩家濒死时完全一致
then it will actually work the same as it does for the player when they're about to die,
我觉得这简直帅呆了
which is pretty cool if you ask me.
化石是我的世界中最稀有的生成结构之一  因为每个区块中它们仅有1/64的生成概率
Fossils are one of the rarest generated structures in Minecraft
as they only have a 1 in 64 chance to generate per chunk.
同时按下键盘上的F3和F4键  可以切换我的世界中的所有游戏模式
Pressing F3 and F4 on your keyboard allows you to switch between all the game modes in Minecraft.
狐狸有5%的几率会叼着绿宝石生成
There is a 5% chance for a fox to spawn with an emerald in its mouth,
要我说 这简直是欧皇附体才能撞见
which is quite a lucky find if you ask me.
当你身处云层下方时 无法透过云层看到上方景象
You are not able to see through clouds when you are below them,
但若置身云层之上 便能俯瞰云海
but you can see through them if you are above them.
真奇怪
Very strange.
制作这期视频时我漏讲了一个冷知识
I forgot to do one of the facts while making this video,
所以我现在半梦半醒地补上这条
so here I am doing it while half asleep.
我的世界中的物品展示框  使用的纹理与白桦木板完全相同
So, item frames in Minecraft use the same texture as the birch planks texture.
看吧？
See?
我要去睡觉了
Okay, I'm going to bed now.
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
南瓜在自然生成时  就已经自带雕刻好的鬼脸
pumpkins used to naturally spawn with their face already carved.
但在如今的我的世界版本中  南瓜自然生成时  不再自带雕刻面容了
In Minecraft today, they don't,
现在你需要用剪刀  自己雕刻南瓜脸了
and you instead have to carve your own pumpkin face with shears.
如果你进入旁观者游戏模式
If you go into game mode spectator mode,
然后左键点击一幅画
then left click on a painting,
你就能透过画作的视角  观察你的我的世界世界
you can see your Minecraft world through the eyes of a,
嗯 画作
well, painting.
站在灵魂沙旁边靠近岩浆时  玩家真的会被点燃
Standing on soul sand next to lava will actually set the player on fire.
哎哟 这可真疼
Ow, this hurts quite a lot.
苦力怕之所以呈现鲜绿色  是因为游戏创始人Notch希望它们能完美融入草丛环境
The reason why creepers are their bright green colour is
because Minecraft creator Notch wanted them to blend in and be
与我的世界早期地形中的草丛融为一体
camouflaged with Minecraft's old world terrain,
当时游戏里的草丛  正是这种鲜绿色
which at the time was a bright green colour.
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在1.5版本更新中游戏曾出现一个bug  恶魂会向玩家喷射钻石头盔  而非它们原本的火球攻击
in the 1.5 update, there was a bug in the game where ghasts would shoot
diamond helmets at the player instead of their regular fireball.
我是说 如果恶魂朝我发射钻石头盔
I mean, if a ghast was shooting diamond helmets at me,
我可不会抱怨 毕竟白捡钻石啊
I wouldn't complain, it's free diamonds after all.
呃 算是吧
Well, sort of.
普通南瓜的藤茎  永远指向我的世界地图的西北方向
The pumpkin stems on regular pumpkins
will always face in the northwest direction of your Minecraft world,
因此它们是非常实用的导航工具
making them very useful for navigation.
你是否好奇过  沙漠神殿主体上方为何会有个小房间？
Have you ever wondered why there's this small room above the main part of a desert pyramid?
我来揭晓答案
Well, I'll tell you.
沙漠神殿二楼的空间  恰好能完美搭建一个全功率信标
So the second floor of the desert temple actually
allows you to perfectly build a fully powered beacon,
令人极度舒适
which is so satisfying.
虽然不确定  是否是开发者有意为之
Whether this was done on purpose,
但二楼确实是安放信标的绝佳位置
I'm not sure, but the second floor is perfect for a beacon.
猪灵蛮兵击败后  会掉落20点经验值
The Piglin Brute mob drops the highest amount of
experience points out of any non-boss mob in Minecraft,
这是我的世界普通生物中经验值最高的
dropping a total of 20 experience.
我是说 这再合理不过了
I mean, I should hope so,
这些家伙打起来可太烦人了
these guys are so annoying to kill.
岩浆怪行走时的摇摆动作  最初是个意外产物
The bobbing animation that the strider makes while walking was initially created by accident.
然而开发者们认为这个效果  用他们原话说
However, the developers thought it was quote,
“既古怪又有趣”于是便将其保留为正式特性
quirky and fun, so it was added as a feature.
我的世界中  目前存在一个关于盾牌的漏洞
In Minecraft, there is currently a glitch in the game when it comes to shields.
所以当你举着盾牌  穿过下界传送门时
So if you hold up a shield while entering a nether portal,
就会发生非常诡异的现象
then something very strange will happen.
一旦进入下界
So once you are in the nether,
你的盾牌会一直处于防御状态
your shield will always be in use,
即便你没有右键点击  它也会持续保持防御姿态
even when you're not right clicking on it to hold it up,
这反而相当实用
which is very useful.
这是因为即使盾牌处于防御状态  你依然可以冲刺和使用武器
This is because you can still sprint and use your weapons while the shield is protecting you.
没错 这真是个绝妙的漏洞
So yeah, a very good glitch.
如果狐狸在雪地生物群系中  试图扑杀一只鸡
If a fox attempts to pounce and kill a chicken in a snow biome,
狐狸可能会  卡在雪地里
then the fox can get stuck in snow.
狐狸兄 你还好吗
You okay there, fox?
看来你需要帮把手
It looks like you could do with a bit of help.
从末影人身上安全获取末影珍珠的有效方法  就是将它们困在船里
A safe and effective way to get enderpearls from endermen is to trap them in a boat.
这是因为一旦末影人被船困住
This is because once the endermen is trapped in the boat,
它们就无法传送逃走
they cannot teleport away,
这样你就能随意击杀它们  获取末影珍珠了
which means you're just free to kill them for the enderpearls.
说实话 我有点愧疚
I'm not gonna lie, I feel a bit bad.
对不起啊 末影人
I'm sorry, endermen.
在早期版本的我的世界中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
史莱姆还没有游泳能力
slimes were not given the ability to swim,
所以每当它们进入水中
so whenever they entered the water,
就会缓缓沉底  最终溺亡
they would just slowly sink to the bottom and eventually drown,
这让我非常非常难过
which made me very, very sad.
不过别担心 现在的游戏里
But don't worry, in Minecraft today,
史莱姆已经学会了游泳  它们能在水中游动  并试图攻击你
slimes have had swimming lessons and they can swim around and attempt to kill you,
这真是太棒了
which is just lovely.
当玩家首次放置附魔台并使用时
When the player places down an enchanting table and uses it for the first time,
弓的第一个附魔等级必定是力量Ⅰ
the first level enchantment for a bow will always be power 1.
在我的世界基岩版中
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
基岩版中营火有个独有特性
there is an exclusive feature in the game when it comes to campfires.
因此如果玩家站在未点燃的营火上时自身着火
So if the player stands on an unlit campfire while they're on fire,
营火就会被自动点燃
then the campfire will actually become lit,
这个细节设计相当精妙
which is a nice attention to detail,
老实说
to be honest.
在我的世界Java版中
In Minecraft Java Edition,
但在Java版中  这一特性并不存在
however, this feature is not a thing.
这是我的世界首次公开的狼群游戏截图
This is the first ever screenshot released for wolves in Minecraft.
如你所见 它们存在显著差异
As you can see, they have noticeable differences,
比如头部纹理的毛色有所不同
such as having different fur color on the head part of the texture.
这张截图让我不禁思考
This screenshot got me thinking,
你觉得我的世界是否应该像加入不同猫咪纹理那样  也为狼群添加多样化外观？
do you think Minecraft should add different wolf textures just like the cats?
在评论区告诉我你的想法
Let me know in the comments below.
尽管下界合金镐是我的世界中最坚固耐用的镐具
Despite the netherite pickaxe being the strongest and most durable pickaxe in Minecraft,
金镐依然是挖掘速度最快的镐
the gold pickaxe is still the pick that minds blocks the fastest.
在我的世界中  利用船只确实可以突破世界边界
In Minecraft, it is actually possible to get out of the world border by using boats.
只需在世界边界旁放置一艘船
Just simply place a boat next to the world border,
进入船内 砰的一下
get into the boat and bam,
你就能突破世界边界
you'll be outside the world border.
不过要小心 因为你可能会因此丧命
Be careful though, because you might die.
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在我的世界开发版早期
in the early versions of Minecraft in dev,
当时游戏里还没有加入工作台方块
the crafting table block was not yet added into the game.
这是否意味着当时玩家无法合成物品？
So did this mean players could not craft items at the time?
不过 事实并非如此
Well, not exactly.
所以如果你按下键盘上的B键
So in in if you press the B key on your keyboard,
按下键盘上的B键  就能打开3x3合成界面  就像使用普通工作台一样
you would open a 3x3 crafting interface as if you were using a regular crafting table.
此外 当时按下I键打开物品栏时
Additionally, when you opened your regular inventory at the time by pressing I,
你会发现这里没有2x2合成格  无法制作小型物品
you'll notice that there's no 2x2 crafting grid to craft smaller items.
没错 尽管开发版中  并没有实体工作台
So yeah, despite there being no physical crafting table in Minecraft in dev,
你依然可以通过按B键来合成物品
you could still craft items by pressing B.
我们都知道 如果攻击一只僵尸猪灵
So we all know that if you hit a zombified piglin,
那么情况就会变得有点疯狂  因为其他所有僵尸猪灵都会对你产生敌意
then things will get a little bit crazy as all the other zombie piglins
will become hostile towards you.
要我说的话 这根本毫无乐趣可言
And if you ask me, that's not fun at all.
这实在太吓人了
It's just very scary.
但如果你能一击秒杀僵尸猪灵
However, if you manage to kill a zombified piglin in one hit,
那么其他僵尸猪灵  就不会对你产生敌意
then the rest of them won't become aggro towards you,
这真是让人松一口气
which is a very relieving feeling.
没错 正是如此
Yeah, that's right.
我打赌你绝对想不到  几秒前我刚干掉了你的同伴
I bet you had no idea that I killed your mate just a few seconds ago.
总之 趁他觉得我可疑之前  咱们赶紧开溜吧
Anyways, let's just move on before he thinks I'm sus.
如果一只苦力怕被施加了药水效果后爆炸
If a creeper is inflicted with a potion effect and proceeds to explode,
爆炸后会留下该药水的滞留效果
it will leave behind a lingering form of said potion,
在我这里就是剧毒效果
which in my case is poison.
在我的世界多人游戏中
In Minecraft multiplayer,
当你的朋友在海边蹲下时
if your friend crouches by the ocean,
透过他的名牌看水面  水会变得透明
then the water itself becomes see-through when you look through your friend's name tag,
这相当诡异
which is rather strange.
谢了Derpy Whale
Thanks for the help Derpy Whale,
这样我看水下清楚多了
I'm able to see underwater a lot easier.
等等 说到水
Wait, speaking of water,
快回水里去
get back in the water,
你可是鲸鱼啊
you're a whale.
在我的世界里  你可以在水下造雪傀儡
In Minecraft, you are able to create snow golems underwater,
但这毫无意义  因为它们会立刻开始掉血
but it's a pretty pointless task as they'll just instantly start dying.
抱歉伙计 为了视频效果我不得不这么做
I'm sorry mate, I had to do it for the purpose of the video,
请原谅我
please forgive me.
但不知为何
However, for some reason,
水下无法生成铁傀儡
you are not able to create iron golems underwater,
尽管生成机制和雪傀儡相同
even though the spawn concept is the same as a snow golem.
搞什么啊 我就盯着个南瓜
What gives man, I'm just staring at a pumpkin,
这可不是我想要的
this isn't what I want,
我想要铁傀儡给我献虞美人
I want an iron golem to hold a poppy out for me.
2009年告示牌刚加入我的世界时
When the sign was first added into Minecraft in 2009,
它们只能以实体形式生成
they could only be spawned in as entities,
当时只能通过按键盘上的B键来生成它们
and this was done by pressing the B key on your keyboard.
一旦生成 它们总会显示：
Once spawned in, they would always say,
这是告示牌的测试
this is a test of the signs,
每行可写15个字
each line can be 15 characters,
但这些实体告示牌看起来确实非常诡异
but yeah, these signs just look really really weird as entities.
众所周知 若在箱子上放置泥土方块
As you know, if you have a dirt block on top of a chest,
你就无法打开箱子
then you are not able to open it.
但若用锄头翻耕这块泥土
However, if you use a hoe on the dirt,
你就能成功打开箱子 正如所见
then you are in fact able to open the chest as you can see.
我现在说话这么小声  是因为这段旁白是凌晨四点录的
The reason why I'm talking so quietly right now
is because I'm recording this fact at 4 in the morning.
总之 继续往下看
Anyways, moving on.
在我的世界早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在1.8版本之前  錾制石砖曾是游戏中最稀有的方块之一
before version 1.8, the chiselled stone brick was considered to
be one of the rarest blocks in the game.
这是由于錾制石砖当时没有合成配方  只能自然生成于
This was due to the chiselled stone brick not having a crafting recipe
and could only be found naturally generated in a
丛林神庙结构中
jungle temple structure,
而丛林神庙本身也是相当罕见的建筑
which are also quite rare as well.
如果你仔细观察疣猪兽的纹理
If you look closely at the hoglin's texture,
你会发现它的一个鼻孔比另一个大
you'll notice that it has one nostril bigger than the other.
帅呆了 疣猪兽！
Looking good, hoglin!
等等 你在干什么？
Wait, what are you doing?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
别杀我！
Don't kill me!
在我的世界基岩版中
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
附魔台
the enchanting table,
放置时  会发出12级的光照强度
when placed, will emit a light level of 12.
但在Java版中
In Java Edition however,
它们则不会发出任何光照
they don't emit any light level,
这就有点逊了
which is a bit lame.
2009年苦力怕首次加入我的世界时
When the creeper was first added into Minecraft in 2009,
它们的纹理采用了更深的绿色调
their texture had a much darker shade of green,
看起来是这样的
which looked like this.
在我的世界早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
Alpha版曾计划实现一个特性 地狱传送门会在主世界生成恶魂
in Minecraft Alpha, there was a feature planned where ghasts
would spawn from nether portals in the overworld.
但这个特性最终未能实装
However, the feature was never implemented.
这倒是件好事   否则绝对会引发大混乱
And good thing too, because that would be absolutely mayhem.
箭矢最初加入游戏时
When the arrow was first added into Minecraft,
合成配方是 一根羽毛
it was originally crafted with one feather,
一根木棍  和一块铁锭
one stick and one iron ingot.
而在现今版本中
Whereas in Minecraft today,
配方改为了 一根羽毛
it's crafted with one feather,
一根木棍和一块燧石
one stick and one flint.
最初幼年僵尸不会在阳光下燃烧
Originally, baby zombies did not burn in sunlight,
这让玩家们不胜其烦
making them extremely annoying for players,
但现在它们也会被阳光灼烧
but now they do.
基岩版中弩的装填动画  实际上与Java版有所不同
The animation for loading a crossbow in Minecraft Bedrock Edition
is actually different to the animation in Java Edition
正如你所见
as you can see.
不知道有没有人尝试过
I don't know if anyone's actually tried this,
但你无法在末地激活地狱传送门
but you are not able to make a nether portal in the end.
指南针永远指向  你创建世界时的出生点
A compass will always point towards the world spawn point
from where you first created the Minecraft world.
不过用这些材料合成指南针毫无意义
However, using the materials to craft a compass is pointless,
因为若将合成配方摆在工作台中
because if you lay out the crafting recipe in the grid,
你会发现指南针预览图标  已经指向了你的出生点
you'll see that the compass preview is already pointing towards your spawn,
因此根本没必要合成它
so there's no need to craft it.
在Minecraft基岩版中
In the Bedrock Edition of Minecraft,
玩家的眼睛现在会像这样眨动
players eyes will actually now blink as you can see.
不知道这算是诡异  还是超酷的功能
I don't know if that's just creepy or a really cool feature.
在Minecraft的Alpha版本中
In the alpha version of Minecraft,
熔炉顶部曾使用过石头材质
the top of the furnace had the stone texture,
使其极易与普通石块融为一体
making it very easy to blend in with regular stone.
你拾取物品的顺序  永远与丢弃时的顺序一致
You will always pick up your items in the same order you threw them on the ground.
如图所示  用未点燃的营火就能造出超酷的桥梁设计
You can create a pretty cool looking bridge design by using unlit campfires as you can see.
这个效果我超喜欢
I really like the look of this.
在Minecraft的早期开发版本中
In an early version of Minecraft in dev,
当移除火把所依附的方块时
when removing the block the torch was placed on,
火把会转移到相邻方块上  而非直接掉落
the torch would move to another block instead of falling off the block,
这设定简直诡异到离谱
which is really weird.
在Minecraft的远古时期
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在Beta 1.9版本中  跳跃竟会莫名给予玩家经验值
in Beta 1.9, jumping would give the player experience for some reason,
这设定有点诡异
which is a little bit weird,
但...行吧
but okay.
同样在Beta 1.9版本中  太阳曾短暂地从方形变成了圆形
Also in Beta 1.9, the sun was changed for a brief time from being a square to a circle,
看起来是这样的
looking like this.
如果玩家试图睡在已被村民占用的床上
If a player tries to sleep in a bed that is occupied by a villager,
村民会被直接踢下床
then the villager is kicked out of the bed.
你怎么能这么残忍？
How could you be so mean?
史蒂夫最初的默认皮肤其实是留着胡子的
The original default skin for Steve had a beard.
或者笑脸 也可能是个笑脸
Or a smile, it could have been a smile too.
Notch 我的世界的创造者
Notch, the creator of Minecraft,
曾计划在游戏中加入爆炸箭
planned to add exploding arrows into the game,
但遗憾的是这个功能最终未能实现
but sadly this feature never made it.
有点伤心 看起来挺不错的
It is kind of sad because they looked really cool
将地毯铺在栅栏上  是玩家自由进出农场的好方法  还能防止敌对生物闯入
Placing carpets on top of fences is a great way for the player
to get in and out of their farm without hostile mobs
因为它们无法攀爬地毯
interfering, as they are not able to climb on the carpet.
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在我的世界开发版早期
in the early versions of Minecraft in dev,
物品堆叠上限曾经是99个  而如今的标准堆叠上限是64个
items used to stack up to 99 instead of stacking up to 64 like they do today.
玫瑰丛不会对穿过的玩家造成伤害
Rose bushes do not apply damage to the player when you walk through them,
尽管如你所见 它们确实长着尖刺
despite them having thorns on them as you can see.
你认为他们应该修改这个吗？
Do you think they should change this?
在评论区告诉我你的想法
Let me know in the comments.
在我的世界旧版本中
In older versions of Minecraft,
在创造模式中攻击敌对生物实际上会引发它们的敌对反应
in creative mode, attacking a hostile mob would actually cause them to be hostile towards you,
这确实有点烦人
which was a little bit annoying.
我永远都会坚持呼吁  直到他们把这个功能重新加回我的世界
I will never stop talking about this until they add this back to Minecraft,
而玫瑰曾经存在于游戏中
and that is that the rose used to be in the game,
但它们被移除了  取而代之的是虞美人
but they removed it and added the poppy instead.
为什么？
Why?
为什么不能两者并存呢？
Why can't we just have both?
在我的世界中  所有向日葵永远都会朝向东方
All sunflowers found in your Minecraft world will always face east,
这使它们成为非常实用的导航标志
making them quite useful for navigation.
末影螨若停留在灵魂沙上  会因窒息而死亡
Endermites will suffocate and die if they are on soul sand.
安息吧 随机生成的末影螨
Rest in peace random endermites.
2014年4月1日愚人节当天
On April Fool's Day, on April 1st 2014,
所有玩家的皮肤都被替换成了村民皮肤  正如你所见
every player had their Minecraft skin replaced by a villager skin as you can see,
这看起来非常滑稽
which looked really funny.
与小史莱姆不同  小型岩浆怪确实能对你造成伤害  如你所见
Unlike tiny slimes, tiny magma cubes can actually deal damage to you as you can see.
若将炼药锅放在户外淋雨
If a cauldron is left outside while it's raining,
它就会像这样慢慢积攒雨水
then it will actually slowly fill up with water as you can see.
徒手破坏黑曜石需要4分10秒
Destroying obsidian with only your fist takes 4 minutes and 10 seconds to do,
很不幸 为了做这期视频  我不得不亲自尝试
and unfortunately I had to do this for the sake of the video,
真希望我没这么干
and I wish I didn't.
如果你从高处坠落即将摔死
If you fall from a high place and you're about to die,
就在即将触地前退出游戏世界
then exit the world right before you hit the ground,
重新加载世界后  你将毫发无损  正如所见
and then load back into the world and you won't take any damage as you can see.
在Minecraft的测试版时期
Back in the beta days of Minecraft,
若有人游玩未授权的Minecraft测试版  便会看到“未授权Minecraft测试版”的提示  附带一个悲伤表情
a message reading Minecraft beta unlicensed copy
with a sad face could be seen if someone was to play Minecraft without purchasing the game.
当苦力怕最初加入Minecraft生存测试时
When the creeper was first added in the Minecraft survival test,
它们最初拥有近战攻击能力  每次能对玩家造成2颗心的伤害
they actually had a melee attack and dealt 2 hearts of damage to the player.
如果玩家进行远距离移动
If the player was to travel,
或传送至距离出生点三千万方块外的位置
or teleport, 30 million blocks from the spawn point,
他们就会抵达世界边界  正如眼前所见
then they will actually reach a world border as you can see.
当热带鱼在Minecraft中生成时
When tropical fish spawn in Minecraft,
90%的概率会呈现屏幕上这22种固定形态
90% of the time they will appear as one of the 22 varieties that are seen on screen,
而剩余10%生成的热带鱼
whereas the other 10% of tropical fish that spawn,
其花纹 体型和颜色完全随机
their patterns, size and colours are completely random,
最终形成2700种自然生成的热带鱼组合
resulting in 2700 different naturally occurring combinations of tropical fish.
在PAX游戏展的1.8测试版演示中
In the beta 1.8 demo at the PAX gaming event,
末影人初次加入游戏时
when the enderman was first added,
死亡后掉落的是钻石（占位符）  而非末影珍珠
they actually dropped diamonds as a placeholder upon death instead of enderpearls.
利用栅栏和地毯  可以搭建出造型奇特的阶梯
You are able to make a really weird looking staircase by using fences and carpets.
这太奇怪了
This is weird.
你可以用雪球杀死烈焰人
You can kill a blaze with a snowball,
看来它们真的不喜欢打雪仗
I guess they just don't like snowball fights.
在任何难度下 玩家从23格高处坠落不会死亡
The most amount of blocks you can fall from before dying on any difficulty is 23 blocks,
因此若从24格高度坠落
so if you fall from 24 blocks,
你就会一命呜呼
you're gonna die.
生存测试版中苦力怕还有个诡异特性  它们会在玩家击杀它们后立即自爆
Another weird feature about creepers in the survival test
version of Minecraft is that they would actually explode after the player killed them,
苦力怕不会通过自爆攻击玩家  而是会在被玩家击杀时爆炸
rather than the creeper exploding on the player as a method of attacking you.
用蛋糕可以做出造型诡异的阶梯
You can create a weird looking staircase by using cake slicers.
末影人最初加入游戏时  眼睛是绿色的  还会散发黑色烟雾粒子
When endermen were first added they originally had green eyes and emitted black smoke particles,
而如今它们的眼睛变成了紫色  还会散发紫色粒子
whereas today they have purple eyes and emit purple particles.
当蜘蛛最初在我的世界中被设计时
When spiders were first being created in Minecraft,
它们原本是棕色的
they were originally brown.
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
恶魂最初发射的火球  其实是燃烧的雪球
the ghast's fireball actually used to be a snowball that was on fire.
我的世界曾有个漏洞  射出的箭矢若击中目标
There used to be a bug in Minecraft where if you shot with an arrow,
你驯服的狼会突然反叛  转而攻击并杀死主人
your tamed wolves would actually turn on you and begin to attack and kill you.
在我的世界Alpha版本中  存在一种地形生成错误区域  被称为“独石”  其外观类似区块加载错误
Monoliths were glitched areas of terrain that could be found
in Minecraft Alpha which resembled chunk errors and they
看起来是这样的
looked like this.
在我的世界生存测试版本中
In the survival test version of Minecraft,
玩家可以通过第二次击打TNT  来取消它的爆炸  这样就能把TNT物品回收回来
players were able to cancel the detonation of TNT
by hitting it for the second time as they'll get the item back rather
而非让TNT爆炸
than the TNT exploding.
如果你手持物品时退出我的世界存档
If you exit your Minecraft world when holding an item,
比如钻石之类的物品
like a diamond for example,
接着创建一个新的我的世界存档
and then create a new Minecraft world,
你会在瞬间看到手中仍握着钻石  随后物品才会消失不见
you will actually see a diamond in your hand for a split second
before returning to having nothing.
如果红狐恰好生成在雪原虎群生物群系中
If a red fox happens to spawn in a snowy tiger biome,
那么它就会变成雪狐  外观看起来是这样的
then it will instead be a snowy fox which looks like this.
不仅如此 如果用红狐与雪狐进行繁殖
On top of that, if a red fox is bred with a snowy fox,
那么幼崽将有50%的几率  生成红狐或雪狐
then the baby has a 50% chance of either a red fox or a snowy fox.
鸡是在我的世界Alpha阶段加入游戏的  而将鸡推下悬崖的机制
The chicken was added into Minecraft in the Alpha phase of the game
and the mechanics for pushing a chicken off the edge
与现在略有不同
of a cliff was slightly different back then.
我们都知道在如今的我的世界中
So we all know that in Minecraft today,
把鸡推下悬崖时  它会扑腾翅膀安全着陆
that pushing a chicken off an edge will cause the chicken to flap their wings down to safety.
然而在我的世界Alpha版本中
However, in Minecraft Alpha,
鸡也会扑腾翅膀落地
the chicken would still flap their wings to the ground,
但实际并不安全  因为无论它们下落时多么轻柔
but it wasn't really safe as regardless of how soft their fall was,
它们依然会受到伤害并死亡
they would still take damage and die.
在我的世界早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
当雪傀儡首次在Beta 1.9版本加入我的世界时
when the snow golem was first added into Minecraft in Beta 1.9,
游戏中存在一个bug 如果玩家手持小麦 雪傀儡就会朝玩家扔雪球
there was a bug in the game where the snow golem would throw snowballs
at the player if the player was holding wheat in their hand.
雪傀儡和小麦有什么过节？
What do snow golems have against wheat?
我只是想做个面包
I just want to make some bread,
这到底怎么回事？
what's going on?
在我的世界早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
也就是Alpha初期阶段
in the early stages of Minecraft Alpha,
游戏曾有个非常独特的特性叫“冬季模式”
there was a really unique feature in the game which was known as Winter Mode.
冬季模式是两种随机生成的世界类型之一
Now Winter Mode was one of the two randomly occurring world types,
另一种则是普通世界类型
with the other being a normal world type.
当创建冬季模式世界时
So upon creating a Winter Mode world type,
玩家会看到四种不同类型的雪花飘落地面
the player would be greeted with four different types
of snowflakes that would fall to the ground,
在露天方块上形成积雪层
creating a snow layer on any block exposed to the sky.
换句话说 你的我的世界会持续不断地下雪
In other words, your Minecraft world would be snowing 24x7.
玩家创建新世界时  有25%的几率生成冬季模式
Now there was a 25% chance for the player to get a Winter Mode world when creating a new world,
而有75%的几率生成普通世界
and a 75% chance to get a normal type world.
然而在我的世界Alpha的后续版本中
However, in a later version of Minecraft Alpha,
生物群系被引入游戏  这意味着冬季模式世界类型被移除  玩家需要自行寻找雪地生物群系
biomes were added into the game which meant the Winter Mode world type was removed
and you would instead have to find a biome with a snowy environment.
在Beta 1.9版本加入雪傀儡生物前
Before the snow golem mob was added into Minecraft in version beta 1.9,
我的世界创始人Notch
Notch, the creator of Minecraft,
原本计划将其命名为“雪人”
originally planned to call the snow golem a snowman.
根据Mojang纪录片所述
We know this as in the story of Mojang documentary,
Notch提到想加入会扔雪球的雪人
Notch mentioned that he wanted to add snowmen that threw snowballs.
听听他怎么说
Take a listen.
另一个建议是做个稻草人
Another thing asuggestion is it to make a scarecrow
*该片段在正式的纪录片中没有
该片段在官方的概念宣传片第二部分中3分17秒处*
因为这很有趣 它用南瓜
Because it would be so fun because they're like a pumpkin here
加上木棍做成 非常可爱
and that's applause noting sticks very cute
我们应该有个能扔雪球的雪人
and we should have snowman that's the throw snowballs
然而当Notch宣布将加入雪人后
However, after Notch revealed that he would add snowmen into Minecraft,
一位Reddit用户建议改称“雪傀儡”  这个名称最终被官方采纳
a Reddit user stated he would instead call the mob snow golems
which later became the official name for the mob.
如果仔细观察
If you look very closely,
你会发现酿造台放置时会发出几乎不可见的亮度等级1的光
you will notice that the brewing stand when placed will emit a barely visible light level of 1.
没错各位  酿造台确实能提供光源
That's right guys, brewing stands provide you with light.
老实说 其实也没啥用  因为我照样啥都看不见
Well, not really to be honest because I still can't see a thing.
将任何喷溅药水朝头顶投掷  比朝脚下投掷效果更佳
Throwing a splash potion of any kind on top of your head
is more efficient than throwing the potion at your feet as the
药水效果持续时间会略微延长  正如你所见
status effect from the potion will last slightly longer as you can see.
箱子是原版我的世界中  少数能在三个维度自然生成的方块之一
The chest is one of the only blocks in vanilla Minecraft
that can naturally generate in all three dimensions which is
主世界 下界
the overworld, the nether,
以及末地
and the end.
若使用双箱并装满潜影盒  则最多可存储90,000件物品
If you have a double chest and store it with
maxed out shulker boxes then you are able to store up to 90,000 items within said double chest.
这存储量可真是惊人
Now that is a lot of item.
在我的世界基岩版中  有个独特设定 箱子在物品栏里会显示为完整方块
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition there is an exclusive feature in the game
where chests will render as a full block within
但放置后却不会
the inventory but not when it is placed.
而在Java版中  箱子在物品栏和放置后的外观一致  这才是本该有的样子
On Java Edition, chests within the inventory look the same
as when they are placed which is how it should be.
游戏中共有16种不同结构  会自然生成箱子
Chests are able to generate in a total of 16 different structures in Minecraft.
没错 几乎每种建筑结构里  都会藏有箱子
That's right, nearly every structure in Minecraft will have a chest.
说到建筑内的箱子
Speaking of chests in structures,
原版中最稀有的战利品当属附魔金苹果
the rarest item you can find within a chest in vanilla Minecraft is the enchanted golden apple.
不过不同建筑中  附魔金苹果的爆率天差地别
However, the rarity of the enchanted golden apple varies across each
structure with the rarest being the mineshaft chest
最稀有的是废弃矿井箱子  仅有0.014%的生成概率
only having a 0.014% chance of spawning.
所以如果你在矿井箱子里  发现了附魔金苹果
So yeah, if you find a mineshaft chest with a notch apple in it,
那你可真是欧皇附体
you are extremely lucky.
在1.3版本中  大箱子物品栏标题  经历了一次颠覆性改动
In version 1.3, a mind-blowing change was made to the large chest inventory title.
没错 在1.3版本之前它叫大箱子  但在1.3版本后它被重命名为...大箱子？
That's right, before 1.3 it was called the large chest
but in 1.3 it was renamed to the large chest?
没错 你听好了  箱子的英文名首字母从此变成了大写
Yep, you heard me, the word chest received a capital C.
多么可爱
How lovely.
一个更广为人知的事实是  每年12月24日至26日期间
A more known fact but every year on December 24th to December 26th,
单个和双联箱子的材质会变成圣诞礼盒样式  看起来就像包装好的圣诞礼物
single and double chests will have their textures changed to
Christmas chests which will closely resemble wrapped Christmas presents.
当幼年村民站在床上时
When baby villagers are standing on a bed,
它们会在床上蹦蹦跳跳  看起来特别有趣
they will bounce up and down on it which looks pretty fun,
老实说
not gonna lie.
在Minecraft的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
床底下的床腿其实是2D贴图  看起来就像这样
the legs underneath beds were actually 2D and looked like this.
不过在1.12版本中
However, in version 1.12,
游戏进行了更新  现在床腿都变成了3D模型并一直沿用至今
a change was made to where beds now have 3D legs and that's how they remain today.
此外 在Minecraft的床还使用2D床腿的年代
Additionally, back when beds had 2D legs in Minecraft,
从特定角度观察床时  会出现一个视觉错误
a visual bug occurred when looking at the bed from a certain angle.
所以当你直接仰视床底时  床腿会完全消失不见  这个现象相当诡异
So looking directly underneath the bed would make the bed
legs completely invisible which was rather strange.
在Minecraft中使用setblock指令放置床时  只会生成半张床  这有点奇怪
Placing a bed by using the set block command in Minecraft
will only place half of the bed which is a bit weird.
老实说 其实并不算
Well, not really to be honest,
这是因为床的模型  实际占用了两格空间
this only happens because the bed is 2 blocks long.
在Minecraft多人服务器的旧版本中
In older versions of Minecraft on multiplayer servers,
你可以传送正在睡觉的玩家  而他们被传送后依然会保持睡眠姿势
you were able to teleport another player while they were sleeping
and they'd still be in the sleeping position when you
这看起来相当滑稽
teleported them which looked pretty funny.
如今在Minecraft中  你依然可以传送正在睡觉的玩家  但传送后他们会立即醒来
In Minecraft today, you can still teleport another player
while they're sleeping but they'll instead be woken up
这肯定会让他们非常恼火  毕竟你打扰了他们的美梦
instantly which I'm sure they'll find very annoying for disturbing them.
兄弟我真不是故意的
I'm sorry man, it was an accident, please!
如果玩家在冰面上放置床
If the player places a bed on ice,
床本身会变得滑溜溜的  就像直接踩在冰面上行走一样
then the bed itself becomes slippery as if you were walking on the ice itself.
用金苹果和虚弱药水将僵尸村民转化为普通村民大约需要3-5分钟
Turning a zombie villager into a normal villager by using a golden apple
and a splash potion of weakness takes roughly 3-5 minutes.
然而在转化过程中若将床放置在僵尸村民旁边 实际上能加速转化进程
However, placing a bed next to the zombie villager
while it's in the curing phase will actually speed up the process.
在Minecraft中  床存在一个奇怪的游戏漏洞
In Minecraft, there is a strange glitch in the game when it comes to beds.
所以 如果你像这样在床边放置矿车然后躺上床睡觉
So, if you place a minecart next to a bed like so and then sleep in the bed,
你会莫名其妙地以睡眠姿势漂浮在床边
you'll for some reason end up floating in the sleeping position next to the bed itself.
看来那辆矿车不想让你在床上睡觉
I guess that minecart doesn't want you sleeping in the bed.
在Minecraft 1.12版本加入彩色床之前
Before coloured beds were added into Minecraft in version 1.12,
制作原版红色床其实有好几种配方
there were quite a few ways to craft the OG red bed.
没错 共有3,456种
That's right, there were 3,456
种不同的合成配方  可以通过所有羊毛与木板组合来制作床  这简直太疯狂了
different ways to craft a bed by using all of the wool and wooden plank
combinations which is insane.
床在下界会爆炸的特性  是因为Notch最初只打算让床在主世界作为重生点使用
The feature of beds exploding in the nether was added
because Minecraft creator Notch only wanted beds to work as a respawn point in the overworld.
说白了 这就是Notch想戏弄整个Minecraft社区  而且他确实做到了
Honestly, that just translates to Notch wanting to
troll the whole Minecraft community and boy did he do it.
如果玩家睡在岩浆里的床上
If a player is sleeping in a bed that is inside lava,
睡在岩浆里的床上  竟然不会受到任何伤害
then you actually don't take any damage from the lava itself.
直到你在岩浆中醒来  开始被活活烧死
That is until you wake up inside the lava and start burning to death,
但我相信你一定能逃出生天
but I'm sure you'll be able to escape,
对吧？
right?
正如你们中有些人所知
As some of you may know,
利用床可以击败末影龙  因为在末地右键点击床会引发爆炸
it is possible to defeat the ender dragon by
using beds due to the beds exploding when you right click on them in the end.
但你们知道吗  大约需要引爆4次床才能击败末影龙？
However, did you guys also know that it takes approximately
4 bed explosions to defeat the ender dragon?
如果你想尝试这个
If you're gonna try this,
只是别在这个过程中把自己炸飞了
just try not to blow yourself up in the process,
这个特性从beta 1.3版本持续到beta 1.8版本  最终在beta 1.9更新中被移除
Now this feature lasted from beta 1.3 to beta 1.8
until it was finally removed in the beta 1.9 update.
在旧版我的世界中
In older versions of Minecraft,
当你躺在床上时
when you slept in a bed,
你可以同时打开物品栏
you could open your inventory at the same time,
这会导致你的角色模型以睡眠姿势显示在物品栏界面上
which resulted in showing your player model in the sleeping position on the inventory screen,
看起来有点滑稽
which looked kinda funny.
你还好吗伙计？
You alright there mate?
你看起来有点累
You're looking a bit tired.
尽管史莱姆是我的世界中的敌对生物
Despite slimes being hostile mobs in Minecraft,
它们却是游戏中少数  不会阻止玩家在床上睡觉的敌对生物之一
they are one of the only hostile mobs in the game
that does not prevent the player from sleeping in a bed.
公平地说 史莱姆看起来天真又可爱
To be fair, slimes look so innocent and cute,
直到它们杀死你之前  你根本想不到它们是敌对生物
there's no way you'd think they're a hostile mob until they kill you of because
床是在2011年2月22日  beta 1.3版本中加入游戏的
Beds were added into Minecraft in version beta 1.3 on February 22nd in 2011.
另外 当床最初加入游戏时
Additionally, when beds were first added into Minecraft,
物品在物品栏中使用的是2D贴图
the item used a sprite texture in the inventory,
而如今在我的世界里
whereas in Minecraft today,
它们采用的是3D纹理
they use a 3D texture.
在游戏中坠落到床上  是个可能救你一命的好方法
Falling onto a bed in Minecraft is a good way to potentially save your life,
因为床能减免高达50%的坠落伤害
as the bed will take up to 50% of normal fall damage.
无论在现实生活还是游戏里
Beds are just amazing in every way,
床在方方面面都棒极了
both in real life and in Minecraft.
好了 我们继续
Anyways, moving on.
天域曾是我的世界规划中的一个维度  设计初衷是与下界相对
The Sky Dimension was a planned dimension in Minecraft
and it was intended to be the opposite of the Nether.
要进入天域维度
Now, to get to the Sky Dimension,
玩家需要躺在床上睡觉  并有几率被传送到这个维度
the player would have to sleep in a bed
and there would be a chance of the player teleporting to said dimension.
然而随着现今末路之地的推出
However, with the introduction of the End Dimension we have today,
天域维度的构想最终被废弃
the Sky Dimension idea was scrapped,
说实话这真的很可惜  因为天域听起来超酷的
which is really unfortunate to be honest because it sounded so cool.
在我的世界旧版本中
In older versions of Minecraft,
当你躺在床上睡觉时
when you went to sleep in a bed,
你在床上是看不到自己身体的
you couldn't see your body in the bed,
这确实有点诡异
which was kinda creepy.
但如今在我的世界里
But yeah, in Minecraft today,
睡觉时  你终于能看到自己的皮肤了
when you sleep, you can actually see your skin,
这才符合常理
which is how it should be.
我更喜欢现在这样
I much prefer it.
如果玩家从高处坠落  下落高度足以造成伤害  但在触地前使用了床
If the player falls from a height high enough to take damage
but uses a bed before they hit the ground,
那么他们实际上不会受到任何坠落伤害
then they won't actually take any fall damage.
直到你从床上醒来时才会受伤
That is until you wake up from the bed.
感谢你啊床铺  我还以为你会救我命呢  结果并没有
Cheers for that bed, I thought you were gonna save my life but nope,
你骗了我
you lied to me.
我现在死了 真是谢谢你啊
I'm dead now, thank you very much.
哇 我刚才听起来是真的生气了
Wow, I actually sounded genuinely annoyed just then.
我没事的 真的
I'm fine guys, I promise.
在Minecraft的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
从Beta 1.3到Beta 1.5版本期间
from Beta 1.3 to Beta 1.5,
当时在下界尝试睡觉时  床铺并不会爆炸
beds did not explode when you tried to sleep in them in the Nether.
然而 试图在床上睡觉反而会
Instead, trying to sleep in a bed did,
什么都不会发生
well, nothing.
这有点虎头蛇尾啊
This is a bit anticlimactic.
总之 继续往下说
Anyways, moving on.
床的底部材质与橡木板材质完全相同
The underneath part of a bed uses the exact same texture as the oak plank texture.
看吧？
See?
一个比较广为人知的事实是  白天遇到雷暴天气时  其实也是可以睡觉的
A more known fact, but it is possible to sleep in a bed during the
daytime if there is a thunderstorm.
在Minecraft基岩版中
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
床的物品栏贴图  实际上沿用了这种老式的2D像素风格贴图
the inventory textures for beds are actually using the old 2D sprite
textures which look like this.
但在Java版中
On Java Edition however,
床的物品栏贴图  则采用了这种3D立体模型贴图
beds use 3D inventory textures which look like this.
Minecraft基岩版的另一个不同之处  在于睡觉时的动画效果
Another difference in Minecraft Bedrock Edition is the animation when you sleep in a bed.
在基岩版中 当你躺在床上时
On Bedrock Edition, when you sleep in a bed,
动画开始时你会仰望天空  然后慢慢将头转向玩家视角
the animation starts with you looking up in the sky
and then you slowly tilt your head towards the player's point of view.
但在Java版中
On Java Edition however,
动画效果就没那么酷了  因为当你躺在床上时
it's not as cool because when you sleep in a bed,
你会直接低头看向自己的腿部
you just instantly look at your player's legs.
在我制作这个视频的时候
At the time of me making this video,
目前我的世界中  共有105种独特的村民皮肤
there are a total of 105 unique villager skins in Minecraft,
比我预想的还要多
which is more than I thought.
你其实可以给村民穿上盔甲
You are actually able to give villagers armour,
这在你想要保护他们时非常实用
which is very useful if you want to protect them.
只需将盔甲放入发射器中  然后对准附近的村民发射即可
This is done by placing the armour in a dispenser
and then dispensing the armour onto a nearby villager.
不过盔甲本身不会在视觉上显示出来
Now the armour itself won't be visually visible,
但防护效果会正常生效
but it will work as intended.
僵尸对村民的仇恨如此之深  即便村民处于隐身状态  仍能攻击村民
Zombies hate villagers so much that they are still able to track
and hunt down a villager that's under the invisibility effect.
不得不说 僵尸这执着劲儿还挺让人佩服
I mean, you have to give the zombie credit,
确实挺聪明的
it's quite smart.
日落时分  我的世界里大多数村民  都会躺到最近的床上  一直睡到天亮
At sunset, most villagers in Minecraft will lay down in the
滚开 安东尼
nearest bed and remain there until morning.
不过绿色衣服的傻子村民  会比其他村民更晚入睡  早上也会起得更迟
However, the green nitwit villager will stay up later
“起来 去吃麦当劳！”
before sleeping and also wake up later in the morning.
这说的简直就是在下
That sounds a lot like me.
好了 继续下一个话题
Anyways, moving on.
如果你仔细观察渔夫村民
If you look closely at the fisherman villager,
你会发现它的衣服上印着一条鱼
you'll notice that it has a fish on it.
哦真的吗安东尼  这还用你说啊老兄
Oh really Anthony, we never would have guessed mate.
所以渔夫村民身上的鱼图案  其实是生鱼物品的旧版材质
So the fish you see on the fisherman villager is actually the old texture for the raw fish item.
这是Mojang特意设计的村民鱼纹  以此致敬最初的鱼类材质
Now this villager fish texture was intentionally done by Mojang
as a nice little callback to the original fish texture we had in Minecraft.
众所周知  在我的世界里我们是用绿宝石和村民进行交易的
So we all know that we use emeralds as a currency to trade with villagers in Minecraft,
但情况并非一直如此
but this wasn't always the case.
没错 当初开发村民交易系统时
That's right, when villager trading was first being developed,
Mojang原本计划在游戏中  加入红宝石矿石和红宝石作为与村民交易的货币
Mojang originally planned to add ruby ore and
rubies into Minecraft as a currency to trade with villagers.
然而 一位我的世界开发者认为  红宝石矿石看起来和红石太相似了
However, a Minecraft developer thought that ruby ore looked too similar to redstone,
于是最终改用绿宝石作为替代货币
which meant emeralds were added instead.
红宝石还是绿宝石？
Rubies or emeralds?
在评论区告诉我吧
Let me know in the comments.
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
僵尸村民曾与普通僵尸  使用完全相同的皮肤
zombie villagers used to use the exact same skin as regular zombies.
唯一的区别在于  它们顶着的是僵尸村民的脑袋  而非普通僵尸的头颅
The only difference is that they of course had
the zombie villager head instead of a normal zombie,
不过 如果你还记得  老版僵尸村民的皮肤
but yeah, if you remember the old zombie villager skin,
那你绝对是我的世界的老玩家了
then you are a Minecraft veteran.
在我的世界基岩版中
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
村民乘船时会发生非常诡异的状况
something very strange can happen with the villagers when they're sitting in a boat.
因此 如果村民在船上时  使用了附近的床
So if the villager uses a nearby bed while they're in the boat,
它们会保持乘船状态  同时呈现睡眠姿势
they'll be put in the sleeping position while still remaining in said boat.
没错 各位
Yep, that's right guys,
村民就这样在船里睡着了
the villager is sleeping inside the boat.
说实话 这睡姿看着还挺惬意的
It looks quite comfy to be honest.
言归正传
Anyways, moving on.
村民是我的世界中少数  乘船或在矿车 时不会呈现明显坐姿的生物之一
Villagers are one of the only mobs in Minecraft
that do not visually sit down when they're sitting in a boat or minecart.
但正如你所见  灾厄村民和僵尸村民却会呈现坐姿
But as you can see, illager mobs and zombie villagers will sit down.
看来村民就是喜欢站着
I guess villagers just love standing.
在Beta 1.9版本加入村民之前
Before the addition of villagers in Beta 1.9,
我的世界创始人Notch最初计划  让村庄建筑由猪人居住
Minecraft creator Nodge originally planned for village structures to be populated by pigmen,
而所谓的猪人  就是这些猪脸村民  它们长这样
which I guess were these pig-like villagers and looked like this.
你们更喜欢猪人  还是现在的村民呢
Do you guys prefer the pigmen or the villagers we have now?
在评论区告诉我吧
Let me know in the comments.
在我的世界中 幼年村民是唯一没有超大头部比例的幼年生物
In Minecraft, baby villagers are the only baby mob in the game that doesn't have a large,
成年体型头部比例的幼年生物
adult-sized head compared to the body.
然而像幼狼这样的生物
However, mobs such as baby wolves,
幼猪 幼牛等其他幼年生物  却都沿用着成年体的头部比例
baby pigs, baby cows and all the other baby mobs use the same head size as an adult mob,
使得它们的头部看起来比身体大得多
making their heads appear much bigger than their body.
与玩家不同  我的世界中的村民  可以在地狱和末地睡在床上
Unlike the player, villagers in Minecraft are able to sleep in beds in the Nether and the End.
“你能闭嘴吗？”
“你还没睡吗？”
“滚”
当玩家尝试这样做时
When the player tries to do this,
就会导致死亡
it will result in death,
这真是太棒了
which is lovely.
开玩笑的 这一点都不棒
I'm joking, it is not lovely,
简直烦死人了
it is so annoying.
好了 继续下一个知识点
Anyways, moving on.
袭击事件发生时  右键点击村民  它们会害怕得冒出冷汗粒子
During a raid, villagers can get scared and
begin emitting sweat particles when you right-click on them,
就像这样
which looks like this.
别怕啊村民老兄
It's okay villager, don't be scared mate.
平原村庄生成的牧师村民  其长袍背面印着某个生物的图案
The cleric villager that spawns in the plains village actually
wears a robe that has a certain mob on the back.
没错 这位牧师穿的是  苦力怕头像长袍
That's right guys, this cleric villager is repping the creeper face robe.
村民的外观和设定  其实源自1993年游戏迷宫魔兽 2里的商店老板
The appearance and concept of villagers were actually
inspired by the shopkeepers from the 1993 game known as Dungeon Master 2.
众所周知 村民能开门
So we all know that villagers are able to open doors,
但不知为何  它们却打不开活板门和栅栏门
but for some reason they cannot open trap doors or fence gates.
村民老兄 你还好吗
You okay there villager?
你看起来有点卡住了
You're looking a bit stuck.
我的世界里的村民  其实还能爬梯子 你看
Villagers in Minecraft are also able to climb ladders as you can see.
然而 它们并不把梯子视为路径 也不会主动攀爬
However, they do not recognise the ladders as paths and don't climb them deliberately,
不过嘛 它们还是能爬上去的
but hey, they can still climb them.
2014年愚人节那天
On April Fool's Day 2014,
Mojang宣布村民占领了我的世界
Mojang announced that villagers had taken over Minecraft,
他们可不是在开玩笑
and they were not joking.
呃 其实确实是在开玩笑 毕竟那天是愚人节
Well actually they were joking since it was April Fool's Day,
但你们懂我意思
but you know what I mean.
总之在2014年愚人节
Anyways, on April Fool's Day 2014,
所有玩家的皮肤都被强制替换成了村民皮肤
everyone's skin on Minecraft was changed to a villager skin,
这张截图展示了服务器当时的景象
and here's a screenshot of how it looked on a server.
用金苹果和虚弱药水将僵尸村民变回普通村民大约需要3到5分钟
Turning a zombie villager back into a normal villager with a
golden apple and splash potion of weakness takes roughly 3-5 minutes.
不过 如果在治愈过程中将床放置在僵尸村民旁边
However, if you place a bed next to the zombie villager while it's in the curing phase,
能显著加快转化进程
it will speed up the transition process.
另一个能加速僵尸村民治愈过程的方块是铁栏杆
Another block that speeds up the zombie villager curing time are iron bars.
没错 如果在僵尸村民周围放置一些铁栏杆
That's right, if you place some iron bars around the zombie villager,
同样能缩短治愈所需时间
it will too speed up the cure time.
在我的世界中 若同时存在铁傀儡和幼年村民
In Minecraft, if an iron golem and baby villager are present,
铁傀儡有概率会向幼年村民递出一朵虞美人
there is a small chance the iron golem will hold out a poppy for the baby villager,
这一幕非常温馨有爱
which is very lovely.
这个暖心的我的世界设定其实致敬了 1986年日本动画电影天空之城
Now this wholesome Minecraft feature is actually a reference to the 1986
Japanese animated movie that is known as Laputa Castle in the Sky.
游戏中的绿色傻子村民原本被称为普通村民
The green nitwit villager in Minecraft used to be called the generic villager.
我更喜欢“傻子”这个称呼 因为这些家伙确实傻得可爱
I much prefer the name nitwit because man these guys are nitwits.
抱歉伙计 开个玩笑
Sorry mate, only joking,
也不完全是玩笑
well not really.
当玩家成功抵御袭击事件后
If the player defeats a raid,
将获得“村庄英雄”状态效果
then you'll be granted with the hero of the village status effect.
获得这个效果后
Now when the player has said status effect,
幼年村民会向玩家赠送虞美人 以此感谢玩家拯救村庄
baby villagers will give the player a poppy as a thank you for saving the villagers,
这个互动非常治愈
which is very wholesome.
在我的世界的午后时分
In the afternoon of a Minecraft day,
除傻子外的所有成年村民都会聚集到钟下开村民大会
all adult villagers apart from the nitwits will gather at the village bell for a town meeting,
这个细节设计得相当精妙
which is a very nice attention to detail.
在1.6版本更新宣传图中
In the artwork for the Minecraft 1.6 update,
背景里潜伏着蓝袍村民的身影 但游戏从未实装过蓝色着装村民
a blue villager can be seen lurking in the background
despite Minecraft never adding a villager with a blue robe.
若村民被闪电击中 会立即转变为女巫
If a villager is struck by a lightning bolt then it will turn into a witch.
在1.4版本游戏文件中
In Minecraft version 1.4,
曾出现过一张愤怒村民头部贴图
a texture appeared in the game files that appeared to be an angry looking villager head,
造型如图所示
and it looks like this.
开发组可能原本计划加入愤怒表情的村民
It seems like Minecraft possibly planned to add an angry villager expression to the game,
但最终未能实现
but never did.
这张愤怒村民贴图在游戏文件中留存至1.13版本
This angry villager head remained unused in the game
files all the way up to version 1.13 until it was officially
直到1.14更新才被移除
removed in Minecraft 1.14.
即使玩家处于隐身状态
If the player is under the invisibility effect,
村民仍会像看得见你一样注视着你
villagers will still look at you as if they can see you,
说实话有点瘆人
which is kinda creepy,
老实说
not gonna lie.
当前版本虽未实装沼泽和丛林村民 但游戏文件中早已存在对应的生物群系村民贴图
In Minecraft, there are villager textures for swamp biomes
and jungle biomes despite swamp and jungle villagers not currently existing in Minecraft.
真心希望未来能实装沼泽和丛林村民
I really hope we get swamp and jungle villagers one day,
那一定会很酷
that'd be really cool.
1.14村庄更新中的村民皮肤设计灵感源自2018年某场现实时装秀
The villager skins that were added in the 1.14 village and pillage update
were actually inspired from a real life 2018 fashion show.
不得不承认
Well, you can't deny it,
村民们的穿搭确实时髦
the villagers have style.
屏幕上显示的是基础村民皮肤模板 现今所有村民变种皮肤都由此衍生
The picture you see on screen is the base villager skin
that was used to create all the unique villager skins in Minecraft today.
虽然这个基础模板不会在游戏中出现
Now, this base villager skin is of course never seen in game,
但正是它奠定了如今丰富的村民皮肤体系
but it's cool it was used as the foundation to create
all the awesome villager skins we have today.
在村庄内攻击任何村民
If you attack any villager within the village,
都会降低你的声望值
your popularity will decrease,
普通交易价格将随之上涨
meaning normal villager trades will become more expensive.
说白了就是村民会记恨你
In other words, the villagers will start hating you.
“这个畜生是谁？”
“滚开！”
如果你以为自己在村民中的声望仅限于那个单一的村落结构 那你可要重新想想了
Not only that, if you thought your popularity among
the villagers was just within that one villager structure, then think again.
所以你打了村民
So if you attack a villager,
整个世界中所有村庄建筑的声望惩罚都会波及
your popularity will decrease within every village structure in your Minecraft world,
所以千万别招惹村民
so just don't attack villagers guys.
当你看见成群的小村民时
If you see a group of baby villagers,
他们常在村庄里追逐嬉戏
then they'll often be running around the village playing tag with each other,
场面相当温馨
which is quite wholesome.
在1.14版本彻底重制前
Before the villager skins were overhauled in Minecraft 1.14,
村民皮肤仅有这几种经典款式
the only villager skins we had were these skins.
安息吧 初代村民皮肤
Rest in peace OG villager skins,
我们永远怀念你
you will be missed.
Java版中若切换至程序员艺术材质包
In Java edition, when the player switches to the programmer art resource pack,
所有村民都会变成戴绿兜帽的造型
all villagers will have a green hood on their head and they all look like this.
下界传送门于2010年10月29日随Alpha1.2版本正式加入游戏
The nether portal was officially added into Minecraft in version alpha 1.2 on October 29th,2010.
然而在传送门正式加入游戏的七天前
However, 7 days before nether portals were added publicly into Minecraft,
恶魂原本设计为会从激活的传送门中生成
the ghast was actually planned to spawn from activated nether portals.
这意味着恶魂原本有可能在主世界生成
This meant the ghast could have potentially spawned in the overworld,
那绝对会引发一场大混乱
which would have been absolutely mayhem.
但转眼11年过去  这个特性至今仍未实装
But hey, here we are nearly 11 years later and we still don't have this feature.
当下界维度首次加入我的世界时
When the nether dimension was first added into Minecraft,
Notch最初将其称为“滑界”
Notch originally referred to it as the slip,
因此我们现在熟知的下界传送门  最初被称为“滑界传送门”
which meant the nether portals we know and love were referred to as slip portals.
我绝对更喜欢“下界传送门”这个名称 而不是“滑界传送门”
I definitely prefer the name nether portals to slip portals,
我是说这名字也太奇怪了吧
I mean what even is that?
若通过指令生成传送门框架方块
If you spawn in a portal frame block by using commands,
你会发现沙砾等下落方块能穿过传送门
you'll quickly discover that falling blocks such as
sand or gravel are able to go through the portal.
当这些方块进入下界后
Upon entering the portal into the nether,
它们会直接以物品形式掉落而不会被销毁
you'll also realise that the sand and gravel just drop as an item and don't get destroyed,
这个机制相当有趣
which is very lovely.
凋灵是我的世界中少数无法穿越下界传送门的生物之一
The wither boss is one of the only mobs in Minecraft
真讨厌
that is not able to travel through nether portals.
让我进去！>:(
“你还好吗凋灵？”
Are you okay there wither?
“来 摧毁我的存档吧”
Here, destroy my Minecraft world,
“这样你会好受些”
that will make you feel better.
回溯早期版本
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
玩家曾利用下界传送门实现物品复制
players were able to duplicate items by using nether portals.
要触发这个复制漏洞
To do this duplication glitch,
你需要搭建一个下界传送门
you'd need a nether portal,
一辆运输矿车  若干铁轨延伸至传送门处
a minecart chest and some rails leading to the portal itself.
玩家将需要复制的物品放入运输矿车  然后缓缓将其推向传送门
Players would then put the item they want to duplicate in the minecart chest
and then slowly push it towards the nether portal.
就在运输矿车即将进入下界时
Then right before the minecart chest enters the nether,
你要立即从箱子里取出物品
you'd take the item out of the chest.
若操作得当  当矿车进入下界时
If done correctly, upon entering the nether,
你会发现钻石仍留在运输矿车中
you'll discover that your diamonds are still in the minecart chest,
这意味着你可以无限复制这些钻石
which means you are able to duplicate them.
在Minecraft生存模式中
In Minecraft survival,
进入下界传送门需要整整4秒
entering a nether portal takes exactly 4 seconds,
而在创造模式中  进入传送门几乎是瞬间完成的
whereas entering a portal in creative mode is almost instant.
在Minecraft的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在Alpha 1.2.2a版本中
in version alpha 1.2.2a,
玩家可以通过按下键盘上的F4键  直接生成已激活的下界传送门
players were able to spawn in activated nether portals by pressing the F4 key on their keyboard.
这个漏洞原本是开发者专用功能  却意外留在了公开发行版中
Now this cheat was accidentally left in a public version of Minecraft
when it was intended to be by developers when
下界传送门最初正处于开发完善阶段时
nether portals were first being well developed.
Notch很快发现调试指令被公开  并于当天紧急发布了Alpha 1.2.2b版本
Notch quickly realised the debug cheat was public to
players and released alpha 1.2.2b on the same day,
移除了生成下界传送门的功能
removing the ability to spawn in nether portals.
我打赌当年玩家们玩这个漏洞玩得不亦乐乎
I bet players had so much fun with this cheat back in the day.
在1.11版本的16w32a快照中
In the 16w32a snapshot for 1.11,
下界传送门存在一个致命漏洞
a bug existed in the game with nether portals.
没错 在这个快照版本里
That's right, in said snapshot,
如果玩家使用钓鱼竿  让浮漂穿过下界传送门
if the player used a fishing rod and let the bobber go through a nether portal,
游戏就会莫名其妙崩溃
then it would crash the game for some reason.
是的 如果你想在这个版本里搞崩游戏
Yep, that's right, if you want to crash your game in this version,
只要对着下界传送门甩钓竿就行
then just use a fishing rod on a nether portal.
在Minecraft远古时期
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在1.7版本之前  下界传送门存在一个漏洞
before version 1.7, a bug existed in the game with nether portals.
正如我所说 如果你在1.7版本前玩过Minecraft
So like I said, if you played Minecraft before 1.7,
透过下界传送门观察时  水体会完全隐形
water would be completely invisible when trying to look at it through a nether portal,
这现象非常诡异
which was very strange.
不仅如此 透过下界传送门观察时  冰块也会完全隐形
On top of this, ice was also completely invisible to players
when trying to view it through a nether portal,
但奇怪的是 岩浆却可以正常显示
yet lava for example was completely fine to look at.
但在1.7版本中
But yeah, in version 1.7,
这个漏洞被修复了
the bug was fixed.
疣猪兽是我的世界中的敌对生物  生成于下界维度  若未做好充分准备它们能轻易置你于死地
Hoglins are hostile mobs in Minecraft that can spawn in the nether
and they can kill you pretty easily if you're not careful.
但如果你站在下界传送门附近  疣猪兽就不会攻击你
However, hoglins will not attack you if you are standing near a nether portal.
这是因为疣猪兽惧怕下界传送门  当它们靠近传送门时
This is because hoglins are scared of nether portals and if they go near one,
它们会立即逃之夭夭
they'll just run away.
没关系的疣猪兽 只是个传送门而已
It's okay hoglin, it's just a portal.
如果你和我一样  有时候懒得挖黑曜石造下界传送门
If you're like me and you're sometimes too lazy to mine obsidian to make a nether portal,
那你并不孤单
then you are not alone.
但别担心 在我的世界中
But not to worry, as in Minecraft,
其实无需开采黑曜石  也能建造下界传送门
it is actually possible to create a nether portal without mining obsidian.
只需将水倒在熔岩上方  直到形成传送门的形状  这样就大功告成了
Just simply place water on top of lava until you
form the shape of a nether portal and there you go,
点燃传送门即可前往下界  再也不用辛苦开采成堆的黑曜石了
you can light the portal and go to the nether knowing you didn't have to
painfully mine a bunch of obsidian.
众所周知 在如今的我的世界中
So we all know that in Minecraft today,
你可以建造各种尺寸的下界传送门
you are able to create nether portals in lots of different sizes.
然而在我的世界的远古版本中
However, in the olden days of Minecraft,
这个下界传送门是唯一能激活的设计  如果你还记得这个
this nether portal was the only design that let you activate it and if you remember this,
那你就是我的世界的老玩家了
then you are a Minecraft veteran.
在我的世界原版中  可建造的最大下界传送门尺寸上限为23x23的黑曜石框架
The biggest possible nether portal you can make
in vanilla Minecraft is a maximum build of 23x23 obsidian,
这个尺寸确实相当惊人
which is honestly pretty huge.
看看这个传送门吧
I mean just look at this portal man,
真是令人叹为观止
it's very impressive.
若你想在末地维度前往下界
If you want to travel to the nether in the N dimension,
那你可办不到  因为无论怎么尝试
then you can't, as no matter how hard you try,
都无法在末地维度激活下界传送门
you cannot activate a nether portal in the N,
所以不必白费力气了
so don't even bother trying.
在我制作本期视频时
At the time of me making this video,
下界传送门已存在近11年
the nether portal is nearly 11 years old,
细想真是令人难以置信
which is honestly crazy to think about.
你们是什么时候开始玩我的世界的？
When did you guys start playing Minecraft?
欢迎在评论区留言分享
Let me know in the comments below.
回溯我的世界的早期岁月
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在游戏的Alpha和Beta版本时期
in the alpha and beta versions of the game,
流动的水能摧毁已激活的下界传送门
flowing water was able to destroy activated nether portals,
这确实相当烦人
which was honestly quite annoying.
然而在如今的我的世界中
However, in Minecraft today,
流动的水对下界传送门已毫无影响
flowing water will do nothing to said nether portal,
这真是极好的改进
which is very lovely.
不过你仍可对着传送门本体放置水直接将其摧毁
You can, however, place a water bucket on the portal itself and destroy it.
在我的世界中 确实存在罕见情况  主世界激活的下界传送门会生成僵尸猪灵
In Minecraft, it is actually possible for a zombified piglin
to rarely spawn from an activated nether portal in the overworld.
不过话虽如此
With that said, however,
这些从下界传送门生成的僵尸猪灵  其生成概率取决于你设定的游戏难度
the spawn rate of these zombie piglins
from nether portals is based on the difficulty you play on.
在简单模式下 生成概率是正常水平
So on easy mode, the spawn rate is normal.
在普通难度下
On normal difficulty,
它们的生成频率会翻倍
they can spawn twice as often.
而在困难模式下  生成频率会提升至三倍
And on hard mode, they can spawn three times as often.
所以没错 如果你在困难模式下游戏
So yeah, if you're playing on hard mode,
你就能看到僵尸猪灵  从下界传送门频繁冒出来了
expect to see a few zombie piglins spawning from your nether portals.
随它们去吧 别管就没事
It's okay, just let them vibe and you'll be fine.
地狱中的恶魂非常烦人  它们会不断朝你发射火球
The ghast mob can be very annoying in the nether as they can intend to shoot fireballs at you,
但一不小心  它们可能会误击并摧毁你的下界传送门
but accidentally hit and destroy your nether portal in the process.
谢了恶魂兄 真是帮大忙了伙计
Cheers ghast, appreciate that mate.
不过别担心 伙计们
But don't worry guys,
如果你的下界传送门在地狱中被破坏了
if your nether portal breaks in the nether,
恶魂还能再次朝你发射火球  重新激活你的下界传送门
a ghast can also reactivate your nether portal by once again shooting another fireball at you.
好吧恶魂 我收回刚才的嘲讽
Okay ghast, I take back my sarcastic comment,
真心感谢你 伙计
I really appreciate it man.
在我的世界中 当你进入下界传送门时
In Minecraft, when you enter a nether portal,
进入传送门时  你会看到这种眩晕动画表示正在准备前往下界
you'll get this nausea animation while preparing to go to the nether,
看起来是这样的
which looks like this.
然而 在我的世界早期版本中
However, back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在游戏的Alpha版本时期
in the alpha days of the game,
进入传送门时的眩晕动画  速度要快得多
the nausea animation while entering a portal moved a lot faster,
这甚至导致部分玩家出现晕动症状
which actually caused motion sickness for some players.
正因如此 传送门动画在Beta版本中被调缓并一直保持至今
Because of this, the portal animation was toned down in Minecraft beta
and it's remained like this ever since.
在我的世界Beta 1.9预发布版4中
In Minecraft beta 1.9 pre-release 4,
下界传送门的材质被修改为  略微暗沉的色调
the nether portal's texture was changed to have a slightly darker look.
此外 传送门框架本身会散发出  暗红色微光而非我们熟悉的紫色光效
On top of this, the portal frame itself gave off a slightly dark
reddish colour rather than the purple colour we're all familiar with.
然而 这个怪异的下界传送门材质改动  在我的世界1.0版本中被撤销了
However, this weird nether portal texture change was reverted in Minecraft 1.0.
下界传送门框架的硬度与基岩完全相同
The nether portal frame has the exact same hardness as bedrock,
这意味着在我的世界中  你无法用拳头或任何工具摧毁它们
which means they're impossible to destroy with your fist or any tool in Minecraft.
在我的世界的旧版本中
In older versions of Minecraft,
在旧版我的世界中  试图用命名牌给村民命名时  反而会触发交易界面
trying to name a villager with a nametag would instead cause the trading interface to open.
为此 玩家必须站在激活的传送门内  并快速为村民完成命名
To counter this, players would have to stand inside of an activated
nether portal and quickly name said villager.
在我的世界1.8版本之前
Before Minecraft version 1.8,
玩家可以通过输入/give指令  将下界传送门框架作为物品生成出来
players were able to spawn in the nether portal frame as an item by using the slash give command.
这意味着你可以将传送门框架收入物品栏  并放置在地面上随心所欲地进入下界
This meant you could have the portal frame in your inventory
and also place it on the ground for you to enter into the nether if you wish.
然而 将下界传送门框架作为物品生成的功能已被移除
However, the ability to spawn in the nether portal frame as an item was removed,
但你仍可通过/setblock指令生成传送门框架
but you could still spawn it in by using the set block command,
这勉强也算是个办法吧
which is something I guess.
僵尸于2009年9月1日  在生存测试版本中加入我的世界
The zombie was added into Minecraft in the survival test version on September 1st 2009,
距今已有12年之久
which was over 12 years ago.
在我的世界中 所有在沙漠生物群系生成的僵尸  有80%的概率会被尸壳替代
In Minecraft, all zombies that spawn in desert biomes
have an 80% chance to spawn being replaced by the husk mob,
看起来是这样的
which looks like this.
这意味着在沙漠中遇到普通僵尸其实相当罕见  因为绝大多数时候出现的都是尸壳
This means it's actually rather rare for a zombie
to be in a biome as most of the time they'll just be husks.
在2013年的Minecraft 1.5更新中
In the Minecraft 1.5 update in 2013,
2013年的1.5版本更新中曾短暂调整过僵尸机制  当僵尸生命值较低时  会对玩家造成更高伤害
a change was briefly made to zombies where said zombies
would do increased damage to the player when the zombie's health was low.
换句话说 当僵尸濒临死亡时
So in other words, when a zombie was about to die,
它们能更轻易地杀死玩家
they could kill the player a bit easier,
这大概给了它们背水一战的机会吧
which gave them a fighting chance I guess.
不过在1.6版本中
However, in version 1.6,
这个特性就被移除了
this feature was removed,
相信很多玩家都为此感到高兴
which I'm sure a lot of players were happy about.
在早期我的世界
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
生存测试版本里
in the survival test version of the game,
僵尸偶尔会穿戴盔甲
zombies would occasionally wear armour.
但在这个版本中
In this version however,
僵尸只会佩戴铁头盔和铁胸甲
the zombies would only wear iron helmets and iron chest plates.
更重要的是 生存测试版里僵尸的盔甲纯粹是装饰性的 并不会提升它们的防御力
On top of this, the armour that the zombies wore in the survival test
were purely cosmetic and did not increase the zombies' protection at all.
说白了 僵尸们只是想耍帅
In other words, the zombies just wanted to look cool,
而且它们确实做到了
and they did.
至少我觉得挺酷的
Well I thought they looked cool,
言归正传
anyways moving on.
在我的世界基岩版中
In Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
有个独占特性 幼年僵尸能骑乘成年流浪猫
there is an exclusive feature in the game where baby zombies are able to ride adult stray cats,
若你想知道那场景有多诡异
and if you wanna know what that looks like,
请看画面
then here you go.
不仅如此 在基岩版里
Not only that, but in Bedrock Edition,
幼年僵尸还能骑熊猫
baby zombies can also ride pandas,
这遭遇战也够离奇的
which too is a rather strange thing to encounter,
喏 效果如图所示
but hey, it looks like this.
我真心疼那只猫啊
I just feel so bad for the cat man,
你看它生无可恋的样子
I mean just look at it.
继续往下说
Anyways moving on.
游戏中多数敌对生物在16格范围内追踪玩家
In Minecraft, most hostile mobs will track the player within 16 blocks of their proximity,
而僵尸的感知距离长达42格
whereas zombies can track the player from up to a whopping 42 blocks away.
这让僵尸格外烦人
This makes zombies rather annoying,
你总能看到它们从老远就冲过来
as you'll always see a bunch of zombies approaching you from very far away.
喂 我看见你了
Yeah, I can see you mate,
能别追了吗？
can you just go away please?
但如果你戴上僵尸头颅
However, if you happen to obtain a zombie head and wear it,
僵尸的探测范围就会缩减50%
then the detection range of the zombies is reduced by 50%.
没错 戴上后它们只能在21格外发现你
So yeah, wear a zombie head and zombies will only be able to see you from 21 blocks away,
虽然还是有点烦
which is still a bit annoying,
但总比42格强
but it's better than 42.
僵尸堪称游戏里最恶毒的生物
Zombies are potentially the meanest mobs in Minecraft,
它们连幼年海龟都不放过
as they will attack and kill baby turtles,
简直丧心病狂
which is just horrible.
这画面太残忍了
This is so hard to watch man,
但为了视频效果不得不放
but I had to show it for the purpose of the video,
实在对不住各位
I'm sorry guys.
如果觉得刚才够过分
If you thought that was bad,
还有更糟的
then it just gets worse,
僵尸会主动搜寻并摧毁24格内的海龟蛋
as zombies will also seek out and destroy turtle eggs within a 24 block radius,
这也太缺德了
which is just awful as well,
没想到游戏真有这种设定
I can't believe this is a thing in Minecraft.
安东尼咱们消消气
Anyways Anthony, let's just relax,
冷静点兄弟 继续往下看吧
calm down mate, let's move on again.
在Minecraft的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在游戏的生存测试版本中
in the survival test version of the game,
僵尸的移动速度能和玩家一样快
zombies could run as fast as the player,
这让玩家根本无处可逃
making them really difficult to get away from.
老兄 离我远点行不行？
Listen mate, get away from me alright?
我宁愿被苦力怕炸飞也不想被你追着跑
I'd rather have a creeper blow me up than have you chase me.
由于僵尸是Minecraft中的亡灵生物
Due to zombies being undead mobs in Minecraft,
伤害药水反而会治愈僵尸
a potion of harming will actually heal the zombies rather than,
而不是伤害它们
well, harm them.
正因如此 治疗药水对僵尸反而会造成伤害
Because of this, a potion of healing will do the complete opposite to zombies.
没错 如果你朝僵尸扔治疗药水
That's right, if you chuck a potion of healing at a zombie,
它实际上会对僵尸造成伤害 最终将其消灭
it will actually deal damage to them and eventually kill them.
在Minecraft开发版的0.31版本中
In the 0.31 version of Minecraft in dev,
僵尸曾被改为完全被动 根本不会攻击玩家
a change was briefly made to where zombies
were completely passive and wouldn't attack you at all.
所以如果你想和僵尸一起放松嗨皮
So yeah, if you wanna chill and vibe with the zombies,
玩这个版本的Minecraft
play this version of Minecraft.
或者你也可以直接玩创造模式
Or you know, you can just play creative mode,
但你应该明白我的意思
but you get my point.
在万圣节期间 Minecraft会变得稍微困难一些 原因如下
During Halloween, Minecraft is considered to be a slightly harder game and here is why.
因此每年10月31日那天
So every year on October 31st,
僵尸有几率生成时头戴南瓜
zombies have a chance to spawn wearing a pumpkin on their head,
这意味着它们在阳光下不会燃烧死亡
which means they won't burn and die in daylight.
所以万圣节白天也要应付僵尸咯
So yeah, enjoy dealing with zombies during the day on Halloween.
不知道为什么我用这种语气说万圣节
Not sure why I said Halloween like that,
不过无所谓 继续吧
but fair enough, moving on.
僵尸是Minecraft史上第二个加入的生物
Now the zombie was the second ever mob to be added into Minecraft,
但第一个生物是什么呢？
but what was the first mob?
首个加入的是人类生物 它们就是顶着史蒂夫皮肤
So the first mob added was the human mob
and they were just Steve skins that would run around aimlessly while flapping
胡乱挥舞手臂到处乱跑 看起来特别滑稽
their arms about, which looked pretty funny.
不过人类生物后来被移除了
However, the human mob has since been removed from Minecraft,
这意味着僵尸成为了Minecraft现存最古老的敌对生物
which means zombies are the oldest surviving hostile mob in Minecraft,
这确实很了不起
which is impressive.
干得漂亮僵尸 我为你骄傲伙计
Well done zombie, I'm proud of you mate.
在Minecraft的早期阶段 从开发版本到Beta 1.7时期
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft from version in dev to beta 1.7,
僵尸死亡时会掉落0-2根羽毛
zombies would drop 0-2 feathers upon death.
如果你还记得这个细节
Now if you remember this,
那你就是Minecraft老玩家了
then you are a Minecraft veteran.
此外 僵尸会掉落羽毛的唯一原因是Notch当时根本不知道僵尸 该掉落什么物品
Additionally, the only reason zombies ever dropped feathers in Minecraft
was because Notch had no idea what zombies should drop when they were killed.
但如今在Minecraft里
But hey, in Minecraft today,
僵尸现在会掉落各种物品了
zombies drop all sorts of things now,
但说实话 我有点怀念它们掉落羽毛的日子  因为那样制作箭矢会容易得多
but I kinda miss it when they dropped feathers to be honest
because it made it quite easy to craft arrows.
好了 继续下一个话题
Anyways, moving on.
在困难难度下  僵尸有48%的几率生成时穿戴金质盔甲
On hard difficulty, zombies have a 48% chance to spawn wearing gold armor.
它们还有37%的几率  生成时穿戴皮革盔甲
They then have a 37% chance to spawn wearing leather armor,
12%的几率生成时穿戴锁链盔甲
a 12% chance to spawn wearing chain armor,
1%的几率生成时穿戴铁质盔甲
a 1% chance to spawn wearing iron armor,
最后 僵尸在困难难度下  有0.04%的几率生成时穿戴钻石盔甲
and finally, zombies have a 0.04% chance to spawn wearing diamond armor on hard difficulty,
这概率简直低得离谱
which is extremely rare.
如果你曾见过穿戴钻石盔甲的僵尸
Now if you've ever seen a zombie wearing diamond armor,
那一定要在评论区告诉我  因为我超好奇你们有没有遇到过这种情况
then let me know in the comments because I'm very curious
to hear if you guys have ever encountered it.
僵尸其实也能在下界生成
Zombies are actually able to spawn in the nether,
原因如下
and here is why.
在困难难度下
So on hard difficulty,
僵尸猪灵在被玩家攻击时  偶尔会召唤增援部队
zombified piglins will occasionally spawn reinforcements when they are attacked by the player.
但大多数情况下
Now most of the time,
增援部队通常只是更多的僵尸猪灵
the reinforcements will just be more zombified piglins,
但有时增援部队中  也会出现普通僵尸
but sometimes zombies can be a part of the reinforcements as well,
这还挺有意思的
which is pretty cool.
在Minecraft的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
当僵尸站在蜘蛛网里时
when zombies were standing inside of a cobweb,
它们不知为何不会在阳光下燃烧
they would not burn in sunlight for some reason.
它们反而会在蜘蛛网里  悠闲地度过白天时光
Instead, they'd just chill in the cobweb and vibe during the daytime,
想必僵尸们对此相当享受
which I'm sure zombies absolutely loved.
我在视频前面提到的僵尸头颅物品  只能通过极其罕见的情况获得
The zombie head item I mentioned earlier in the video
can only be obtained from a very rare scenario.
因此玩家只有在闪电苦力怕爆炸  并杀死附近的僵尸时才能获得僵尸头颅
So players can only obtain a zombie head if a charge creeper explodes and kills a nearby zombie.
所以啊 遇到闪电苦力怕可得当心点
So yeah, be careful of the charge creepers.
如果尸壳恰好身处水下
If a husk ever happens to be underwater,
它会在水下停留30秒后  转变为普通僵尸
then it will turn into a normal zombie after vibing there for 30 seconds.
这只新转化的僵尸若继续留在水中  再过30秒就会变成溺尸
This newly turned zombie will then turn into a drowned mob
after an additional 30 seconds if it continues to stay there underwater.
为什么不帮我:(
在我的世界的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在我的世界早期版本中  幼年僵尸在白天阳光下是不会自燃的
the baby zombie mob used to not burn in sunlight during the daytime.
这使得它们成为游戏中最烦人的生物之一
This made them one of the most annoying mobs ever,
正当你白天想悠闲度日时  总会有烦人的幼年僵尸  突然冲过来袭击你
as you'd just be trying to vibe during the day
when a stupid baby zombie would come charging towards you and potentially
把你干掉
kill you as well.
但幸运的是 在1.13版本中
But luckily, in version 1.13,
一项改动使得幼年僵尸  现在也会在阳光下燃烧
a change was made to where baby zombies would now burn in the sun,
这改动简直大快人心
which I am so happy about.
如果僵尸在燃烧时攻击玩家
If a zombie attacks the player while they're on fire,
那么玩家也有一定几率会被点燃
then there's a small chance that the player will be set on fire as well.
不仅如此 游戏难度越高
On top of this, the higher the difficulty you're playing on,
僵尸点燃你的概率就越高
the higher the chance the zombie has to set you on fire,
所以玩极限模式时  千万要当心燃烧的僵尸
so watch out for burning zombies if you're playing hardcore.
截至我制作本期视频时
As of the time of me making this video,
目前我的世界中  关于美西螈存在一个漏洞
there is a glitch present in Minecraft when it comes to axolotls.
所以如果你用拴绳拴住一只美西螈
So if you attach a lead to an axolotl,
拴住后它就会像这样  绕着玩家飞速转圈
then it will begin to walk extremely fast around the player as you can see.
至于原因 我也百思不得其解
Why they do this, I have no idea,
但这只美西螈显然乐在其中
but this axolotl is absolutely loving it.
这个漏洞对多只美西螈也有效
This glitch also works with more than one axolotl,
意味着你可以用拴绳拴住一群美西螈  它们就会绕着玩家急速转圈
which means you can attach multiple axolotls to a lead
and they'll all just circle around the player very quickly,
场面简直混乱到极点
which just looks absolutely mayhem.
好了 我们继续
Anyways, let's move on.
美西螈被加入我的世界的原因  是因为现实中的美西螈濒临灭绝
The reason why axolotls were added into Minecraft is
because axolotls in real life are critically endangered,
我觉得Mojang借此提高公众意识的做法很棒
so I think it's great that Mojang are raising awareness for them.
游戏中美西螈会攻击所有水下生物  除了海龟和海豚
In Minecraft, axolotls will attack all underwater mobs except turtles and dolphins.
这包括溺尸
This includes the drowned,
守卫者 远古守卫者
guardian, elder guardian,
鱿鱼 荧光鱿鱼 以及各种鱼类
squid, glow squid, and fish.
如果有生物或玩家攻击美西螈
If a mob or player attacks an axolotl,
它们有1/3的概率会装死
then they have a 1 in 3 chance of playing dead.
这意味着它们会装死10秒钟  同时恢复2颗心的生命值
This means they'll pretend to be dead for 10 seconds while recovering 2 hearts of health.
现在屏幕上显示的是未发布的绿色变种美西螈  看起来还挺酷的
The axolotl you see on screen is an unreleased green variant of the mob and it looks kinda cool.
2020年我的世界直播回顾截图中  就曾出现过这只绿色美西螈
Now, the green axolotl was seen in the Minecraft live recap screenshot in 2020,
但它从未在我的世界1.17版本中正式加入
but it was never officially added in Minecraft 1.17,
说实话这真是挺遗憾的
which is a shame to be honest.
除此之外 在洞穴与山崖更新第一部分的预告视频中
On top of this, in the trailer video for part 1 of the Caves and Cliffs update,
尽管绿色美西螈并未出现在正式更新中  但在预告视频里仍能短暂看到它的身影
the green axolotl can briefly be seen despite it not appearing in the update itself.
安息吧 绿色美西螈
Rest in peace, green axolotl,
我们会想念你的
you will be missed.
在我的世界中 可以通过使用热带鱼桶来繁殖美西螈
In Minecraft, axolotls can be bred by using buckets of tropical fish,
但不能直接使用热带鱼物品来繁殖
but not by using the tropical fish items themselves.
这是因为在现实中
This is because in real life,
美西螈只以活鱼为食
axolotls will only eat living fish.
而你知道的 装在桶里的鱼仍然是活着的
And you know, the fish that are still in the buckets are still alive,
所以这个设定非常合理
so this feature makes sense.
蓝色美西螈的生成概率设定为1/1200
The reason why blue axolotls have a 1 in 1,200
之所以设定为1/1200的生成概率  是因为现实世界中仅存约1200只
chance to spawn is due to the fact that there are only roughly 1,200
野生美西螈存活于现实世界
axolotls left in the wild in real life.
说实话 读到这个事实挺让人难过的
Honestly, reading that fact is rather sad,
不过我很高兴Mojang通过游戏提高了人们对美西螈的关注
but again, I'm glad Mojang is bringing awareness to axolotls.
尽管体型娇小
Despite their small size,
但正如你所见 游戏里的美西螈能爬上方块
axolotls in Minecraft are able to climb up blocks as you can see,
说实话这动作萌翻了
which looks so cute to be honest.
它们正努力向上爬
I mean, they're getting there,
这份努力值得鼓励
they're trying.
加油啊小家伙
You've got this axolotl.
当玩家击杀与美西螈战斗的怪物时
If a player kills a mob that an axolotl is in combat with,
美西螈会给予玩家几秒钟的生命恢复效果
then the axolotl will give you the regeneration effect for a few seconds,
它们真是太贴心了
which is very lovely of them.
用桶右键点击美西螈就能把它装进桶里带走
Right clicking on an axolotl with a bucket allows you to collect it,
获得一桶美西螈
giving you a bucket of axolotl,
看起来就像这样
which looks like this.
这样你就能把美西螈桶放进发射器里  只需点击按钮就能放出美西螈
This allows you to put the bucket of axolotl in a dispenser
and dispense an axolotl at the click of a button.
你还可以把美西螈桶放进物品展示框里  展示这些可爱的小家伙
Another thing you can do with a bucket of axolotl is
put the bucket inside of an item frame and display your lovely axolotl.
说实话 这感觉有点残忍
I'm not gonna lie, this feels a bit mean to be honest.
美西螈本该在水中悠游自在  却被困在展示框里动弹不得
The axolotl should be chilling in the water and instead it's just trapped in an item frame,
这实在太残忍了
which is horrible.
好了 我们继续
Anyways, moving on.
蓝色美西螈是唯一一种  现实中不存在的变种
The blue axolotl is the only variant that is not based on a real life axolotl.
而其他四种美西螈  确实都源自现实中的品种
The other four axolotls on the other hand are in fact based on real axolotls,
这个细节设计得相当用心
which is a nice attention to detail.
不过别担心  蓝色美西螈依然很有趣  它是根据Reddit网友建议加入游戏的
But don't worry, the blue axolotl is still very interesting
as it was added after somebody suggested it on Reddit.
于是Reddit用户DarkEyesFlame提议  我的世界应该加入稀有的蓝色美西螈  其外观
So Reddit user known as DarkEyesFlame mentioned that Minecraft
should add a rare blue axolotl and have its appearance be
参考精灵宝可梦系列中水跃鱼的外观
based off Mudkip from the Pokemon series.
所以没错 蓝色美西螈并非源自现实生物
So yeah, the blue axolotl isn't based on real life,
但它确实参考了宝可梦里的水跃鱼
but it is based off Mudkip from Pokemon,
这真是太酷了
which is very cool.
无论剩余耐久度多少  木制工具在熔炉中燃烧时间完全相同
A wooden tool will burn exactly the same in a furnace regardless of its remaining durability.
这意味着耐久度耗尽的旧木制工具  在熔炉中的燃烧效果  和全新的木制工具完全一样
This means a used up wooden tool with low durability will be just as effective as a new wooden tool.
在熔炉加入我的世界之前
Before furnaces were added into Minecraft,
物品是通过另一种方式熔炼的
items were smelted in a different way.
所以在我的世界开发早期版本中
So in the early versions of Minecraft in dev,
玩家可以通过将矿石扔在地上  然后用打火石点燃来熔炼它们
players could smelt ores by dropping the item on the ground
and setting them on fire with a flint and steel.
这确实是种非常独特的熔炼矿石方式
Definitely a very different way of smelting ores,
不过嘛 至少这方法确实管用
but hey, at least it worked.
岩浆桶是我的世界中最高效的熔炉燃料  单桶就能熔炼多达100个物品
A lava bucket is the most effective furnace fuel to use in Minecraft
as it can smelt up to a whopping 100 items,
这简直太疯狂了
which is crazy.
在我的世界Java版中
In Minecraft Java Edition,
如果你徒手破坏熔炉
if you break a furnace with your hand,
需要整整17.5秒
it takes exactly 17.5 seconds to destroy it.
值得一提的是 这样破坏熔炉并不会使其掉落为可拾取物品
With that said, the furnace will not drop as an item,
所以别像我一样浪费时间做这种傻事
so don't waste your time doing this like I did.
但在我的世界基岩版中
On Minecraft Bedrock Edition however,
而在基岩版中  徒手破坏熔炉同样需要17.5秒
destroying a furnace with your hand again takes 17.5 seconds,
但熔炉会作为物品掉落
but the furnace will drop as an item.
每个物品在燃烧的熔炉中  熔炼时间恰好为8秒
The smelting time of each item in an active furnace is exactly 8 seconds.
在我的世界Alpha版本中
In the alpha versions of Minecraft,
熔炉的顶部材质原本是石头制成的
the top part of the furnace texture was made out of stone,
看起来就像这样
which looks like this.
这让熔炉更容易隐藏在其他玩家视线中  因为你可以把它和普通石头混在一起
This made the furnace a lot easier to hide from other players
as you could blend the furnace in with regular stone,
这设计相当酷
which was pretty cool.
不过在我的世界Beta版本中
However, in Minecraft Beta,
熔炉顶部获得了专属的新材质
the top part of the furnace received its own texture.
在雪地生物群系生成的村庄建筑里会有这种覆雪的小屋
The village structures that you find in snow biomes
contain these snowy houses that look like this.
在这些雪屋中 你能找到的箱子里有9.9%概率会出现熔炉
In said snowy house, you can find a chest that has a 9.9% chance to have a furnace inside of it.
如果你在游戏中驯服了猫  同时点燃了熔炉
If you have tamed a cat in Minecraft and have an active furnace going,
就要做好准备——你的猫会蹲在燃烧的熔炉上取暖
then be prepared as your cat will sit on the lit furnace to keep warm.
在InfDev版本的某个时期
At some point in Minecraft version InfDev,
曾短暂修改过熔炉材质  移除了“面部”特征 改用全周统一贴图
a change was briefly made to where the furnaces no longer had a face
and used the same texture all around.
说实话
Yeah, I'm not going to lie,
这看起来实在太奇怪了
this does not look right at all,
不过这个改动很快就被撤销了
but yeah, this change was quickly reverted.
InfDev版本另一个短暂存在的改动  是熔炉的冶炼速度
Another change that was briefly made in the InfDev version of Minecraft
was the furnace smelt time.
正如之前提到的
So, as mentioned before,
原版每个物品需要熔炼8秒
each item in Minecraft takes 8 seconds to smelt,
但在InfDev中 曾改为仅需4秒就能完成
but in InfDev, a change was made to where items only took 4 seconds to smelt.
没错 物品在InfDev里熔炼快得多
So yeah, items smelted a lot quicker in InfDev,
不过这个改动也很快回滚了
but this change was quickly reverted.
使用煤炭块熔炼物品  比单用煤炭更高效
Smelting items in a furnace by using a block of coal is more efficient than using just the coal itself.
因为1个煤炭块能熔炼80个物品
This is because 1 block of coal can smelt up to 80 items in a furnace,
而9个单独煤炭只能熔炼72个
whereas just using 9 coal in a furnace will only smelt up to 72 items.
在Alpha早期版本中
In the early stages of Minecraft Alpha,
放置熔炉时存在一个烦人的bug
there used to be a really annoying bug in the game when it came to placing furnaces.
当时放置熔炉时
So in Alpha, when you placed a furnace,
它总是会背对玩家放置
it would always place facing away from the player,
想在房子里摆放时特别让人恼火
which was really annoying when you wanted to place it in your house.
当年我可没少为这个生气
I hated this back in the day.
等等 我是在录视频吗
Oh wait, am I recording?
继续往下说
Moving on.
在Minecraft中使用setblock指令
Using the setblock command in Minecraft,
使用setblock指令可以生成  一个已激活的熔炉  即点燃状态的熔炉
you can spawn in an already active furnace known as the lit furnace.
这个点燃的熔炉正如其名
Now this lit furnace is in the name,
因为它会始终保持点燃状态  正如你现在看到的这样
as it will always stay lit as you can see,
即便里面没有任何物品在熔炼
even if there's nothing smelting in it,
这确实有点奇怪
which is kinda weird.
一组64个煤炭块能让熔炉持续工作14.2小时
A 64 stack of coal blocks will smelt items in a furnace for a total of 14.2 hours,
这相当于游戏里的42个昼夜
which is equivalent to 42 Minecraft days.
没错 煤炭块确实能让熔炉运行很久
So yeah, the coal blocks can smelt for quite a long time.
默认情况下 熔炉的界面只显示
By default, the GUI of a furnace simply says,
熔炉
well, furnace.
但如果你在铁砧上  给熔炉重命名
However, if you rename the furnace in an anvil,
那么界面名称就会变成  你为熔炉重命名的那个名字
then the GUI name will change to whatever you renamed the furnace to,
这功能相当酷
which is pretty cool.
熔炉在工作时
Furnaces, when active,
会发出13级的光照亮度
emit a light level of 13,
比火把的光照稍暗一些
which is slightly dimmer than a torch,
而火把的光照等级为14级
which gives off a light level of 14.
熔炉会照亮周围的所有方块
Furnaces will light up the blocks all around it,
尽管只有正面发光
despite it only being lit up from the front.
然而在1.4版本的快照阶段
However, during the snapshot phase of the 1.4 update,
当时对熔炉的照明效果  进行了一项实验性改动
an experimental change was made to the lighting of furnaces.
所以在快照12w39a中
So in snapshot 12w39a,
当时修改了熔炉的照明范围  使其仅能照亮正前方的方块
a change was made to where the furnaces only lit up the blocks in front of them.
但在后续的1.4快照中
But then in a later 1.4 snapshot,
这一改动又被撤销了  因为显然它导致了性能问题
the change was reverted as apparently it was causing performance issues.
在Minecraft的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
在1.9战斗更新之前
before the 1.9 combat update,
玩家可以生成我之前提到的  点燃状态的熔炉物品
players could spawn in the lit furnace I mentioned earlier as an item.
从1.3到1.7版本期间
So from version 1.3 to 1.7,
点燃的熔炉物品在物品栏中  显示效果是正常的
the lit furnace item looked as it was supposed to look in the inventory.
但在1.8版本中
However, in version 1.8,
出现了一个bug导致点燃的熔炉物品  在物品栏显示为缺失材质
a bug formed where the lit furnace item changed to have a missing texture in the inventory,
看起来就像这样
which looked like this.
奇怪的是当你放置点燃的熔炉时
This was strange because when you placed the lit furnace,
它看起来很正常  但物品形态却完全错乱
it looked normal, but the item just looked all messed up.
不过在1.9战斗更新后
But then in the 1.9 combat update,
这已经无关紧要了  因为游戏移除了生成点燃熔炉物品的功能
it didn't matter anyway because the ability to spawn in the lit
furnace as an item was removed from the game.
工作台于2010年1月30日  在Minecraft的in-dev版本中加入游戏
The crafting table was added into Minecraft in version in-dev on January 30th in 2010.
这意味着工作台  现在已经12岁了
This means the crafting table is now turning 12 years old,
这简直让我觉得太不可思议了
which is absolutely crazy to me man.
Minecraft中首个加入的合成配方  绝对是个奇怪的存在
The first ever crafting recipe added into Minecraft was definitely a strange one.
合成系统首次在Minecraft in-dev版本中引入  而史上第一个合成配方  竟然是箭的配方
So crafting was first introduced in Minecraft in-dev
and the first ever crafting recipe was a recipe for the arrow.
现在要合成这支箭
Now to craft this arrow,
你需要用8个苹果  按照国际象棋棋盘的样子排列
you would need 8 apples in the shape of a chess plate like this.
没错 我可不是在开玩笑
Yep, I'm not joking guys,
这就是开创一切的原始合成配方
this was the crafting recipe that started it all.
这难道不美妙吗？
Isn't it just beautiful?
锻造台是我的世界中的一种方块   玩家可以用它将钻石工具和盔甲升级为更高级的
The smithing table is a block in Minecraft that players can use
to upgrade their diamond tools and armor into the more powerful netherite type.
目前锻造台的界面是这样的
Now the smithing table currently looks like this,
但当它最初在Minecraft 1.14版本加入时
but when it was first added in Minecraft 1.14,
它原本的界面长这样
it used to look like this.
如你所见 旧版锻造台的纹理确实与工作台的纹理极为相似
Now as you can see, the old texture for the smithing table
definitely closely resembles the crafting table texture,
这很可能意味着在被替换之前这只是个临时占位纹理
which likely meant this was a placeholder texture before being changed.
在工作台加入我的世界之前
Before crafting tables were added into Minecraft,
玩家们无法
players couldn't, well,
制作物品
craft.
好啦好啦 我开玩笑的
Okay, okay, I'm joking.
好吧 某种程度上算是
Well, sort of.
那么 在工作台出现之前
So, before crafting tables were a thing,
玩家只能通过按键盘上的B键  来进行合成操作
the only way players could craft was by pressing the B key on their keyboard.
没错 按下B键就能随时随地  调出3x3合成网格进行物品制作
That's right, pressing B meant players could use a 3x3
crafting grid to craft items anywhere they wanted to,
仔细想想
which now that I think about it,
这让我的世界变得简单了些  因为连工作台都不需要
made Minecraft slightly easier because you didn't even need a crafting table,
在我的世界手机版的早期
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft Pocket Edition,
也就是现在的基岩版
which is now known as Bedrock Edition,
手机版玩家无法通过工作台  合成石质方块
players were not able to craft stone-related blocks using the crafting table.
他们必须使用旧版的切石机  才能制作心爱的石砖
Instead, players on Pocket Edition had to craft their beloved stone blocks by
using an old variant of the stone cutter.
这就是旧版切石机的模样
Now the old stone cutter looks like this,
相信很多手机版老玩家  看到这个方块都会倍感怀念
and I'm sure many Pocket Edition players are getting very nostalgic just seeing this block.
言归正传 工作台其实还能当熔炉燃料使用
Anyways, moving on, the crafting table can be used as fuel to smelt items in a furnace.
一个工作台可以熔炼  整整1.5个物品
Now a single crafting table is capable of smelting a whopping total of 1.5 items,
这简直太疯狂了
which is absolutely crazy,
真的
I know.
说真的 还是老老实实用煤炭吧
Honestly, just stick to using coal.
如果你曾低头查看工作台底部
If you are ever in a situation where you look underneath the crafting table,
你会立刻注意到底部纹理和橡木木板完全相同
you'll instantly notice that the bottom texture is using
the same texture as the oak plank's texture.
刚才我说了好多次“纹理”这个词
I said texture quite a lot just then.
继续往下说
Anyways, let's carry on.
等等 我刚才讲到哪了？
Wait, what was I saying again?
对了 工作台底部的纹理  确实和橡木木板一致
Oh yeah, the bottom part of the texture is the same as the oak plank's texture,
但在MC远古版本里
but back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
比如Indev时期
in the early versions of InDev,
工作台底部其实是另一番景象
the bottom texture for the crafting table was actually different.
没错 在Indev版本中  工作台底部显示的是橡木原木纹理
That's right, looking underneath the crafting table in InDev would
bless the player with the oak log texture instead,
这种纹理出现在工作台上  显得格外诡异
which looks extremely weird being on a crafting table,
但也说得过去
but fair enough.
你们有没有专门花时间  好好欣赏过工作台的纹理细节？
Have you guys ever taken some time out of your day to just look and admire the crafting table?
没有？
No?
就我一个人？
Just me?
好吧 如果你和我一样怪
Well, if you are as weird as me,
你就会发现工作台的纹理上  其实藏着一把小锤子
you'll notice that the crafting table texture features a hammer,
一把锯子  还有一把钳子
a saw, and some pliers.
对我来说 这始终有点奇怪
Now to me, this has always been kind of strange.
而且我一直以为  那把钳子其实是苦力怕的脸
Also, I always thought those pliers were a creeper face,
这么多年才发现真相  感觉被欺骗了这么多年
and I feel lied to after all these years,
话说回来  你们觉得这些工具  应该被加入Minecraft吗？
Anyways, do you think any of these tools should be added into Minecraft?
如果觉得应该加入的话  请在评论区告诉我  你觉得该加哪个工具以及理由
If so, let me know in the comments which one you think it should be and why.
你们还记得以前  每次合成完物品后材料还留在合成格里的时代吗
Oh my god, do you guys remember back to a time where
whenever you'd leave items in the crafting grid after crafting,
那时候一退出合成界面  材料就会直接掉在地上？
they'd just be thrown on the floor when you exited the crafting interface?
倒也不算特别烦人
Now, it wasn't insanely annoying.
其实 你知道吗
Actually, you know what?
确实烦人 因为一关掉合成界面  你的钻石可能就直接飞进岩浆里了
It was, because there was a chance your diamonds
could just go flying into the lava after closing the crafting grid,
那简直能毁掉你一整年的好心情 说真的
which would just ruin your year to be honest.
好吧 确实  90%是你自己的问题  10%是游戏的锅
Okay, sure, 90% of that would be your fault and 10% the game,
但这确实是游戏本身的机制问题
but it was still in the game,
所以我也能稍微甩锅给游戏
so I can kind of blame it.
不过呢 在1.12版本中
But yeah, in version 1.12,
游戏做出了改动  现在关闭合成界面时  留在合成格里的物品会自动返还
a change was made to where closing the crafting interface
would now return any items that you left inside the crafting grid to your inventory,
这个改动让我举双手双脚赞成
which was a change I welcomed with open arms,
让我告诉你
let me tell you.
如果你还记得工作台以前叫合成台的时候
If you remember when the crafting table was called the workbench,
那你绝对是我的世界的老玩家了
then you are a Minecraft veteran.
没错 从Alpha版到Beta 1.1版本期间
That's right, from Minecraft Alpha to Beta 1.1,
合成台在游戏里确实被正式命名为工作台
the crafting table was officially known as the workbench.
不过从Beta 1.2版本开始
However, since version Beta 1.2,
我们就改称它为工作台 并沿用至今
we have called it the crafting table and it's remained that way ever since,
这个改动我很喜欢
and I love it.
在基岩版的早期版本中
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
锻造台原本是用一个工作台加一块圆石合成的
the smithing table used to be crafted by using one crafting table and one cobblestone.
但在现在的版本里
However, in Minecraft today,
锻造台配方已经改为四块木板加两个铁锭 不再需要工作台
it no longer uses the crafting table as the smithing table is now
crafted with four planks and two iron ingots.
不仅如此 在基岩版中
Not only that, but in Minecraft Bedrock Edition,
制箭台最初也是用一个工作台加一支箭来合成的
the fletching table was originally crafted with one crafting table as well and one arrow.
不过现在游戏里
But yeah, in Minecraft today,
制箭台的配方已改为四块木板加两块燧石
the fletching table is crafted with four planks and two flint.
工作台经历过多次细微的材质改动
The crafting table has gone through many small texture changes.
所以当工作台最初加入我的世界时
So when the crafting table was first added into Minecraft,
它最初是这样的纹理 现在回看真是充满怀旧感
it looked like this, which looking back at it now is a very nostalgic texture.
但在1.14早期快照中
But then in an early 1.14 snapshot,
它的材质被改成了这样
it was changed to look like this.
但这个改动并未持续太久 在后续的1.14快照中材质又进行了微调
But that didn't last very long as it was slightly changed again in a later snapshot for 1.14.
但这个版本同样没持续多久  最终在1.14.1版本中
But that didn't last very long either as finally in 1.14.1,
工作台的材质最终定型为现在这样  并一直沿用至今
the crafting table was changed for a final time to look like this and it's remained that way ever since.
工作台能在我的世界的某些结构中自然生成  具体包括以下几种建筑
The crafting table is able to naturally generate
within a few structures in Minecraft and those are as follows.
首先 女巫小屋中会生成工作台
First of all, crafting tables will generate within a witch hut,
这还挺酷的
which is pretty cool.
其次 冰屋的地下室里也会生成工作台
Secondly, a crafting table can be generated within the basement of an igloo structure,
这设计非常贴心
which is very lovely.
接下来 你还能在某些村庄小屋中发现工作台
Next up, you can find some crafting tables in some small village houses,
这简直令人惊叹
which is mind-blowing.
是啊 谁能想到村民家里会有工作台呢？
I know, who would have thought villagers would have crafting tables?
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
我是在夸你呢
I was complimenting you.
最后 掠夺者前哨站外围的帐篷里也会生成工作台
Then finally, a crafting table is able to be generated
within the tents that generate outside the pillager outpost.
所以如果你胆大在那个帐篷里合成
So if you're good at craft in that tent,
可要当心那些掠夺者
be careful of those pillagers,
老兄
man.
你肯定不想被弩箭射中脸
You don't want to get a crossbow arrow to the face.
那样可就...没法继续合成了
Just couldn't, well, craft.
好吧好吧 我开玩笑的
Okay, okay, I'm joking.
也不完全是
Well, sort of.
在我的世界早期版本
Back in the earlier days of Minecraft,
Alpha测试阶段有个特殊世界类型  那里永远在下雪
in the alpha days, there was a unique world type where it would be snowing all the time.
在Alpha版本创建存档时
In alpha, when creating a save,
你有四分之一的几率生成永恒雪原世界  无论走多远都会持续下雪
you had a one in four chance to get the world
where it would always be snowing no matter how far you travel.
如果你还记得这个特殊世界类型
Now, if you remember this unique world type,
那你绝对是MC老玩家了
then you are a Minecraft veteran.
你们记得游戏最初没有疾跑功能吗？
Do you guys remember when sprinting was not in Minecraft?
没错 在Beta 1.8版本之前
That's right, before the beta 1.8 update,
游戏里根本没有疾跑
sprinting was not in the game,
这意味着在MC世界里赶路  耗时更长也更折磨人
which meant getting from point A to point B in your Minecraft world
took a lot longer and it was a lot more painful.
在 Youtube 上关注原作者：iDeactivateMC
原标题：400 Minecraft Things You Didn't Know Existed
原视频上传日期：2025年6月25日
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
♥无偿翻译，用爱发电♥
如果你喜欢这个视频，请多多支持和评论哒~ o((>ω< ))o
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！
该视频已删减部分与“500个我的世界老玩家应该知道的事”
视频重复的片段。原视频完整时长为2小时30分